[Music]
Hello and welcome to the Junkyard Love.
>> Hey, everything's going to be all right.
>> It's all good. It's all good.
>> The Junkyard Love podcast.
[Music]
to the junkyard.
>> Mr. Blake Hole, welcome to the podcast.
Thank you for your time. I appreciate
you, man. It's uh I'm looking forward to
chatting. If I had to uh put you in a
rear naked choke and say, give me a bio,
what what would uh what would come out?
>> Yeah. Uh I am
I always want to go with like accolades
right the achievements I've done this
I've done this um but I think you know
um I'm a mathematician that works in uh
software engineering and machine
learning um I have a very diverse
background across many different things
you know uh healthcare um pure
mathematics statistics machine learning
as we just talked about, you know,
multi- multifunctional human being.
Maybe
>> that's a good way to put it.
>> I know. I have I have a friend who uh
works in the in live events just like as
a creative everything and she she
introduced me to the term multiaceted
and I know it's not the first time I
ever heard it, but I I love considering
my uh like art and career path as as
multiaceted. So,
>> yeah,
>> you seem very multifaceted.
>> Exactly. It Yeah, multiaceted. Yeah.
Well, what's what's been on your mind
lately, man? What's um you know, so
something that you and I connect, we're
longtime friends. Um you know, we
haven't stayed like incredibly in touch,
but I think uh something that's jumped
out for both of us is like we you know,
we both love like Ramdas, and it seems
we've gotten into meditation and kind of
the spirituality and that sort of thing
as we have gained some age in our years.
Um so I I I definitely want to like lean
into that. I definitely want to talk
about AI today. Um, but I was kind of
just curious like like what's been on
your mind lately, you know, like what's
been kind of like the loudest creative
thoughts or pressing thoughts or even
just like personal um what's what's been
kind of you your personal obtuse
thoughts lately? What have you been
thinking about?
>> Yeah, I've been in therapy for like a
year now. Um, and what's actually been
on my mind a lot is my therapist like a
month or two ago said
we were we were talking about stuff and
she and things kind of were getting a
little bit tense and I have this
tendency to just like re remove myself
or start explaining but like oh yeah
that sucks but you know like it's cool I
got all this going on and stuff and she
kind of slowed me down and she was like
I feel most connected with you when
you're feeling and I was like,
"No one's ever said anything like that
to me before." And you know, it it just
like I think about it all the time. It
changed so much about me. All of a
sudden, I felt
even like, you know, we were talking
about the meditation stuff. Like I
picked up meditation, got into Ron Das
also like a year and a half ago. Started
really kind of thinking about those
things. And so I had this like level of
calm, but like knowing that there's
someone in the world that's like,
"Yeah, I like when you feel like I'm I'm
here with you when you feel." Uh it was
just like life-changing. Super super
strange. And
>> yeah.
>> Do do you feel like it um you know, a
lot of the core of of feelings is
allowing them like letting feelings to
be there? It sounds like so on the
surface, but sometimes that is the
biggest thing is we have so many
responses and ways that have
we've utilized to our benefit to protect
ourselves from like very intense
feelings sometimes and sometimes it
makes it to where we just um you know we
numb we numb or move away from from big
feelings in some sort of way. So, what's
what's it been like for you? Like like
what has that you know trying to bring
intellect into a you know a feeling is
difficult but but what's that been like
for you to think about you know like
have you been noticing where you've been
kind of like not letting your feelings
be okay in your relationships and stuff?
What do you think?
>> Yeah, I think that there's two
components to it. So like on one side
you know uh we as a culture we kind of
work on this model that
when we have emotions it's not uh worth
experiencing that we should you know
emotions are just noise you know we
should be very logical we should always
think about things we should always you
know all that kind of stuff like you
should never listen to your emotions and
uh I had a teacher in college once that
was like emotions are information. You'd
be stupid to just ignore it, you know,
like and I think that that's a powerful
statement. It's great to think about
emotions as information rather than just
like foundational truth that can be
philosophized and you know we can like
come to some kind of dialectic or
something about our feelings always like
it can't just be that like oh I feel sad
because this is happening in the world
or whatever. So the way that that that's
like the first part about it and then
the second part which is more to your
question about how it has changed things
for me or how I've noticed it. I think
that
uh I actually tie this back to what Rahm
Doss talks about where like you can't
become nobody before you become
somebody, you know? You got to like go
through it. And I remember sitting with
my therapist saying like,
I'm great at the second half. Like
fantastic at being like, okay, like
we're going to cope with these emotions.
We're going to like go forward. Like I'm
going to go on a walk. I'm going to do
all these things to like stop the
feelings, but like I haven't done that
first work of feeling it, you know? I
haven't become somebody in my emotions.
And that makes me feel less safe for
people around me. And it feels less
authentic. And so it's really nice to
kind of start showing up and start being
a little bit more patient with myself
and with others around me. I think it
makes me a safer person to be around cuz
people can kind of like trust like, oh
yeah, Blake's upset. Blake's happy. Like
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> It's actually there. God, that's so
nice. I I think you use the word au
authentic very nicely there. I think
that is kind of what what the core of it
is. I um I'm I'm drawn to think about uh
it it was profound for me to have
someone repeat like I had heard it
before but someone was talking about on
a podcast about how like oh even Jesus
flipped tables too
>> and like there was something about when
I first heard it like when someone had
repeated it back on a podcast just kind
of the context that they were putting it
in
>> was just like this sudden oh man okay
like it's okay like I'm a human I'm
going to have emotions and and rejecting
them or trying to make a new identity of
some dude who doesn't have bad emotions
ever cuz he's just super peaceful and
he's the meditator cat like you know
it's like you're you're you're not
allowing to that au authenticity like
you said you're kind of like
>> you're blocking off what's really
happening in favor of trying to just
feel good all the time which is like the
like biggest maybe not the biggest like
one of the more for me personally anyway
on the spiritual path
like trying to make sure everybody knows
I'm like this meditative I trying to
make sure everybody knows I'm I'm real
calm and for the most part like without
even thinking about it trying to control
anybody's image of me. I can come
across, you know, I meditate in the
mornings and so it generally does make
me calmer for the rest of the day. Like,
but that's not
like it's still okay to get upset and
like sometimes you got to you flip a
table, you know? I mean, it's not like
>> I I don't know. It's Yeah. What just
allowing emotions it turns out to be
like one of the more difficult lifelong
parts of our journey, right? Allowing
>> Yeah. Yeah. You're talking about a
dharmic anger, right?
>> Like anger that serves a per purpose
that comes from a place inside yourself.
That's
>> true. That's, you know, when Jesus
starts flipping tables, he's not doing
that. Uh just cuz he's angry, you know,
just cuz it's like this doesn't serve
any purpose. I'm just freaking out. You
know that's like anger to serve a
purpose of highlighting his point or to
you know bring something better into the
space rights talks all the time about
how Maharaji would say to him like get
out of here
>> jiao you know and it was always kind of
just like you know it was intense and
stuff but you could tell it was coming
from a place of love
>> and I think that when you talk about
>> anger and and emotions that we as a
society tend to just kind of be like
people tighten up around. You definitely
want to work towards like Yeah. just
feeling the full range of emotions and
being safe in it,
>> right? Yeah. I mean, think about as as a
young kid, you know, we're we're
observing the adults around us to learn
just how to do things and how to react
and stuff and
>> and you know, like I I think it's a
mistake for us as as the adults in the
room to
reject what we're really feeling or
like, you know, have a have a young kid
think that when they're frustrated, what
they really need to do is like be happy
cuz people don't like you when you're
when you're angry. People aren't going
to your friends don't want to hang out
with you when you're when you're upset
cuz and there's this balance I'm sure
like you know I I I'm not a father but
I'm sure there is a balance of like
teaching them hey it's okay to have that
anger like hey I'd be frustrated too
that makes sense hearing them out being
with them but let's feel through that
emotion not as a way to negate it right
away or like all right you got to feel
it so you can get rid of it you know
that's another trap but allowing it to
be there
>> allowing it to work through and then on
the other side when you're when you're
bi biology when your body isn't so, you
know, attacked or um, you know, at at
one with the emotions like just kind of
the tension we all get when it comes to
any sort of deep emotion, especially
anger. Um, yeah, we can kind of like
allow it to go through and then, you
know, feel the the lessening of our
shoulders and like the our face kind can
kind of drop like, okay, I let that
thing pass through. It had something to
teach me. I was angry because in the
future when that same thing comes up,
it's okay to be angry, but I can
actually like not let it catch me off
guard so much because I've now learned a
little bit, you know? It's uh it's the
biggest pro. I I don't know. I love that
you mentioned that like right off the
bat, man. Like allowing yourself to feel
what you're really feeling. That's
profound.
>> Yeah. You got to you got to go through
it. It's not like you're saying. Yeah.
We we definitely just as a society it
would be better if if uh in my opinion.
Not that I'm king of the world or
anything, but
>> Yeah, you are. Here's the key.
>> The big giant skeleton key.
>> Tell us what to do. This is Have you
seen Idiocracy? That movie where
>> Oh, yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. We're so smart and spiritual. We
get to solve all the problems.
>> Exactly. Well, now to put uh Gatorade on
our flowers and stuff, you know.
That is crazy. I want to rewatch that
show, but I also think it's going to
feel more like a Black Mirror episode
than it will like old movie.
>> Yeah, it was weird even back when it
came out just in terms of like how
poignant it felt. And it's weird. Yeah.
Thinking about it now being like, "Oh,
so much of it is more relevant."
>> Yeah. I mean, it it always it always
sparks the movies like that, you know. I
think I've been thinking a lot. It's
kind of hard not to, but thinking about
like Brave New World in 1984 and like
those kind of like future predictive
books that are kind of like laying out
where what seem where we seem to be
headed in some ways. Um,
but I
I don't know some sometimes those books
are just like I don't know be becoming
aware of that stuff is just is just
heavy and it's you wonder where ideas
come from. I guess basically is like,
man, somebody 40 years, 50 years, 60
years before this thing happened had
these ideas and they sat down in their
apartment and just started like writing
them out in in creating a book that
like,
>> you know, I mean, like the writers of
the Simpsons, how do they keep
predicting everything, you know? It's
it's interesting where uh just kind of
where our ideas about society as as a
whole kind of come from. I don't know
where I was going with that, but it took
us on a left field adventure. It wasn't
that left field cuz Aldis Huxfle uh is
very interesting actually in his you
know he wrote Brave New World and
he did uh Masculine so he was like an
early adopter of psychedelics and then
he like changed his whole view on things
and started writing these books that
were more about like getting in touch
with yourself and stuff. So not too left
field.
>> Yeah. Hey see it's all full circle isn't
it? Uh it's all connected.
>> It's all connected like mushrooms man.
It's all connected.
>> Um I was actually listening to uh Have
you heard of Paul Stamuts? He's a
mushroom guy, mologist. Yeah.
>> He was um he was just yesterday on the
new episode of of Joe Rogan. I listen to
a lot of Joe Rogan's podcast
>> and he was on there again. Um
>> and just man, some of the concepts that
he talks about just expand my mind into
the world. I also did a little bit of
mushrooms yesterday. So that's um in in
that same ballpark. It's so connected,
man. Um
but uh
I I don't know where I was going with
that. Um the
yeah I mean I I think psychedelics in in
general they cause that self-reflective
you know so what something we we were
talking about at the you know just not
long ago was feeling emotions that are
really there. I remember so I did um I
did micro doing of mushrooms a few years
back. Um, I've done a couple macro
doses, but I had done micro dose just
like very
um I did the pulse damage protocol. I
forgot exactly how much I had it all
measured out and you do lion's mane, you
do nasin with it and and whatnot. And I
did that for like four or five months.
And dude, one of the biggest takeaways
that I had and it was frustrating for a
while because you go in thinking you
know what you need to fix about yourself
when it comes to psychedelics. Like,
>> oh, I need to work on blah blah blah.
And then like this just random left
field thing comes in. You're like, I
don't want to process. That sounds gross
to process and not fun. I don't want to,
but I want to work on this thing. And
mushrooms and psychedelics aren't like
that. Um, and what one thing that I had
to work with, and it I feel it made me
better at my job. It made me more um
kind of intertwined with my own
masculinity, for lack of maybe a less
broad term, was um
>> allowing myself to feel anger at work.
Like sometimes people do some [__] [__]
at work and you go, "Hey man, that's
enough of that [__] shit."
>> Like enough or like someone's like
jokingly playing with you. Like
>> I'm not too caught up in in some of the
hierarchy stuff. Like if you want to
like, you know, like give me some [__]
or you know, I come from like I've
worked plenty of bluecollar jobs and so
sometimes you just kind of give each
other [__] Um, but there'd be some
instances where before I was micro doing
where I would take a little bit too much
and it would kind of like um, you know,
the the person's trying to take me out.
They're trying to take me out of the
knees or like bring me down to some
level, whatever. And most time I'd just
brush it off. But it's funny when I'm on
mic micro doing mushrooms, you think I'd
be like even more airy fairy about it.
But I'd stand up for myself and tell
people like, "No, dude, you're not going
to talk to me like that. Like, it's not
okay." No. Nope. We're not going to do
that. Let's Let's back up. Let's uh,
listen to what you just said. Do you
think it's okay for you to talk to me
like that? Which sounds sounds so weird
to like take it into this podcast
conversation, but um
>> No, you're fine.
>> Yeah, I I think uh
mushrooms in psychedelics and kind of
like lessening that continuous story
that we always have going on. You know,
we're always in lost in our stories.
There's not a damn thing wrong with it.
It's part of our experience. But
breaking the the patterns of those
stories, kind of getting out of those
grooves of our default network in our
brain can kind of give us a little bit
of space to like, you know what, I'm
going to flip this [__] table because
because these people aren't listening to
me. Like, hey yo, like you're talking to
me in a disrespectful way and this
environment
>> requires that you that that that you
respect me. That sounds so intense
again, but um you know, it's some
sometimes it just happens in in a work
environment. So, um, yeah, just allowing
oursel, have have you had, you know,
outside of that that conversation with
your with your counselor recently, have
you had any moments, um, just like as a
man, as as a, you know, uh, like growing
up and like trying to I don't know if
the word masculine works works for you
or, but just kind of like leaning into
allowing aggression, allowing um, like
more precise communication, those sorts
of things. I don't know. Does that spark
anything for you, Blake? Like just being
more masculine? I don't know.
>> Yeah, let's let's get into this. This is
an interesting
>> I don't know. We're We're going here. I
guess we're going to talk about the
>> I'm I'm on for the ride. Uh yeah. No,
this is a very interesting question. Um
so I was raised by a single mother my
whole life. Um occasionally, you know,
she would date somebody and eventually
they would come around and stuff, but
nothing really kind of
uh stuck or anything like that. So, I
never really had like a male model in my
life. I mean, I kind of did sometimes,
like, you know, there was my brother. My
brother was always kind of coming in and
out and stuff. Uh, anyways, you know,
just typical like, you know, low-inccome
Kelso kids stuff. And so, my
template for masculinity was built a lot
around,
you know, what my mom wanted for men to
be like. And then also what society
expected men to be like. And I think
that there was like
anger really wasn't a part of it. Like
my mom with her own issues just really
wanted like a sensitive, gentle man who
had an edge.
>> And so and so in a lot of ways I, you
know, I was very sensitive as a kid.
Super, you know, raw, very just like
very in touch with my feelings. I loved
everybody. I I would like leave for
school and like always every single
morning I would go in front we had this
big window in the front of our house and
I would go in front of it and like you
know blow a kiss like wave and stuff. Uh
and my mom loved that kind of stuff. So
I was like very
very much um kind of pushed towards like
sensitivity is good. So, I got a lot of
the maternal uh feminist feminist uh
feministic qualities that people get um
typically just reserved for women in our
society when they're coming up. Got a
lot of that at home and stuff. And then
I would get bullied a little bit. You
know, I go and hang out and I was kind
of just a little bit weird cuz I would
cry over tiny tiny tiny things. Um I was
just very sensitive. I wanted everybody
to be nice. There was a lot of like
feeling in it. And so that kind of got
calloused over as I got older. And then
masculinity kind of took the place of
that. It became like I have to be hard.
This is how you this is how you do it.
And again then we get that uh emotions
are not good. No one should listen to
their emotion. Everybody should be
logical.
And so I took on a very like it wasn't
necessarily toxic masculinity, but it
was definitely like an idea of
masculinity that had to do with being
here, being all brain, all like you had
to be sharp, I have to be, you know,
high achieving, I have to just do, you
know. But yeah, I think that's where
masculinity kind of got intertwined with
me for sure.
>> Yeah. And then so and so now you find
that it's something that you're actively
working on as you're 33, right? 34.
>> Yeah. 33.
>> Yeah. I mean, how interesting is that?
It's like something you have to like,
all right, let's go back in the old
folders
>> and and and see like, you know, not not
necessarily that, hey, this is something
about me that I need to change, but hey,
let's look into like why I was the way
that I was. How did I get there? and and
what could I apply, you know, what new
knowledge and practice at this age in my
life at 33 could I apply to kind of like
smooth out those, you know, the the way
I see it, I always use the um the
analogy of kind of like the body armor,
you know, especially when we're kids and
teens, especially if we're ultra
sensitive,
>> we've got to put on some layers to like,
you know, protect ourselves. Like
you're, you know, you're talking about
like all in the head, this
intellectualize, like let's bring logic
to this. And sometimes we put so much of
our energy up here, it's like, wait,
let's let's keep our heart protected.
Let's put some armor over our heart so
people can't like, while I'm thinking up
here, people can't like poke me in the
heart with an arrow, you know?
>> Um, but yeah. So, so I I wonder like how
similar
>> cuz I I I find a lot of what you were
saying. I find a lot of similarities in
in me, you know. Um, and so I wonder how
many other dudes who are around our age
are are kind of reapproaching what uh I
don't know if it's the correct
terminology to call it like you know uh
you know masculine and feminine um
energies. Those words are super intense
nowadays
>> but um yeah I I think I think we
wouldn't be shocked to learn that
there's plenty of other men who are kind
of
>> trying to revamp their their
understanding of their own emotions and
uh approaching those things. you know,
>> I hope so. Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> There's there's kind of a crisis with
that, too. Um, men definitely, in my
opinion, as a member of the group of men
need to revisit. Yeah.
Revisit it because it it does things
like, you know, at at high levels in
businesses, for example, at the seauite
level, you get women that come in, but
they've adopted male characteristics.
And so they're in those spaces
not bringing feminine energy in like I
would like to see. Uh I think that
there's a lot of that that happens too
because men are too unwilling to change,
right? Like we're the power structure.
We're, you know, the ones that are
running the the game. And so it's like,
yeah, you can come up here, but you got
to play our game, you know, because
we're not going to change.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Don't don't come up here
with a new game. We don't know how to do
your new game. It doesn't work for our
our suppression of emotions. So,
>> no. Yeah. It definitely makes the space
a little a little strange. So, it would
be nice if more men could come out and
definitely
just like you were saying, it's not
necessarily that you even need to be you
need it's not even necessarily that you
need to change. You just need to be more
mindful about why you're doing the
things that you're doing.
>> And that's where meditation really comes
in handy,
>> you know. Oh, absolutely. Yeah. I mean,
I love uh uh PM Pemma. Have you heard of
any of her work? She's a meditation
teacher. Oh my god, dude. I'll Sounds
familiar. Maybe.
>> I'll send you a book. Uh P E M A space C
H O D R O N. Pemma children. Um
>> God, she has so many good books. She
she's one of those teachers that so in
my um I got certified in mindfulness
meditation teacher training and she was
like our main curriculum like our main
one book that we read was uh I think
it's called Start where you are
>> by her um
>> beautiful name.
>> God's so good. She she has so she has
some uh lectures on YouTube and some
stuff on Audible as well as her her
written text. Um, man, she she talks
about how
like it's it's a pretty profound
concept, but change wanting to change
oursel is in itself an act of aggression
towards who we already are.
And it's like this, oh [__] you know,
like, you know, you probably also heard
some variation of like the the one the
one who thinks they need to change is
the one that needs to change, you know,
and that's not that's not saying like,
hey, you who you are with all your
[__] is okay. In some essences it is
actually who you are with all your
[__] is okay.
>> But um it's not about villainizing the
parts of you that aren't good, aren't
like zen and chill and accepted by
society and accepted by others. It's
allowing those things to be there and
not feeling that you need to change them
um by like no let's let's reject this
part of who I am and what I'm actually
experiencing but more of like this
>> oh you see it you know like you sit in
meditation and you see the way that your
mind is you see the way that you are and
it's
>> it's frustrating cuz you're like god I'm
super annoying sometimes like why am I
keep doing that but it's also just it's
all an invitation to like oh I Okay, I'm
a little annoying sometimes.
>> Oh, oh, I'm a little h sometimes. Well,
that's okay. It's who I am. You know,
it's not just by recognizing it and
bringing the intellectual side of our of
our mind into like, all right, let's
shine the spotlight onto these patterns
of who I am. And just because you shine
a spotlight doesn't mean you get to
freaking change it or get rid of it or
something, you know? you still if if
you're going fishing with the with like
and you're in Louisiana and you're
shining the the light into the water,
like just cuz you see a fish doesn't
mean you're eating, you know? You still
got to
>> you still you still got to I don't know
where that Louisiana fish reference came
from, but um
>> it's a deep cut, I guess.
>> Deep Louisiana cut.
>> Yeah.
>> Um but yeah, no, I I just love that. I
think uh meditation is a constant you
know you uncover layers about yourself
but that is kind of one of the bigger
continuous journeys that we that we
embark on is like oh am I am I rejecting
a part of me to try to change it so I
can be better and accept myself more
>> oops oops
oh I don't need to do that I I can just
I can just allow it um okay so man I I
would love to
>> uh if you have any more thoughts on that
please please interrupt my rambling but
I would love to just kind of learn more
about your meditation practice and kind
of how you first stumbled into it.
>> Yeah. No, that's great. Um, I think
it's it's funny cuz what you were what
you were just saying, you know, about
like really seeing like who we are, you
know, witnessing our thoughts and kind
of like,
you know, cultivating the witness. The
person says, "Oh, there's anger. Oh,
yep. Yep. Here it is again. Oh, there's
my jealousy."
you know, something that's there uh is
is truly a beautiful skill, I think, uh
for people to to gather and and
strengthen. For me,
what
I had tried meditating many times over
the years, uh just like I've tried
journaling many times over the years. Uh
and I just I just couldn't get into it.
And um I remember one time I was just
like, "Okay, I'm just going to do it.
I'm just going to do it. I think I heard
Ron Doss talking about, you know, just
some idea of what meditation is supposed
to do and it just kind of clicked with
me. I was like, "Oh, okay." Like that's
that makes sense. I'm not supposed to be
doing anything except
just stay here, you know, or like focus
on the muscle. Like whatever you want to
do, just do that. Just let it let it
happen. Anytime I like, you know, go
away, I'll just What does it feel like
to do that? Okay. Okay. No, don't worry
about feeling. That's just like breathe.
>> You have one thing to do. And um doing
that I did it like the first time I was
like I'm committed.
I was very serious about it. I'm like
I'm committed. I'm going to something's
going to happen. Yeah.
>> And uh sure enough, after like 40
minutes of just like forcing myself to
just like
and just like letting it happen, it was
like my thoughts kind of ticker taped
out
>> and all of a sudden I was like there was
like that, you know, that beautiful
space in between a thought where it's
like you're free.
Oh, and then the next thought comes in
and it and it like you know it's it's
fun now a year and a half later to like
have those moments because I can be like
and here's the next thought
>> peace next thought and like not that
long ago mostly I just do meta
meditations so I love to just like
meditate for a little bit and then may
all beings be happy may all beings be
free you know do
>> can can you expand on what I I I assume
people listening are probably have heard
ramble on about meta meditation. Will
you give me a brief explanation of what
meta meditation is?
>> Yeah, the way that I use it is uh mostly
as a way to deal with uh the aggression
that I have just in general because I
feel like it it currently as I feel it
closes me off. So for me, med meditation
is a way to open myself back up to feel
more compassionate to truly like be love
and compassion.
And so uh as meta meditation is the
loving compassion meditation.
I love to use it. So I do the regular
meditation get myself kind of you know u
not regular regular meditation but just
chilling. And then uh once I kind of get
to a space where it's like okay I'm
feeling really like in myself then I say
the mantras the the three different
versions of the mantras which are may
all beings uh be safe. May all beings be
healthy. May all beings live with ease.
And may all beings be free. And then
then I do may I be this way, you know.
And then may you be this way. And
usually when I'm at the you part, I'm
thinking of someone something uh that
has brought me,
you know, some kind of anguish in some
way. So I'm going through a breakup.
Oftentimes when I do medit med
meditation I'm thinking of my ex and my
ex is on my puja table. I use I use
every every morning when I wake up I'm
like I have a picture of Maharaji and
some other people and I'm like good
morning Maharaji. Good morning grandpa.
Morning
Janet move on.
>> Yeah and just kind of try and like
soften that that feeling cuz yeah it's
not great. So anyways that's the way
that I use meta meditation.
>> I love that. Yeah, I um I I think
meditation is is super powerful because
it's really a lot of meditation is
another
we're really trying to break the the
patterns of our conditioning. You know,
we're trying to break our um you know,
get a little sliver, like you said, that
space in between, you know, our stimulus
and response. A lot of times we can live
our whole life just in response and we
like don't even realize that there's
been stimulus popping us off this whole
time, you know. Um but uh so so with
meta meditation, so when you when you
first started doing it, I found and I've
heard other meditation teachers talk
about this. I found that it took me a
long time to get to where I could wish
myself love. Like that was genuinely
difficult. I which is that that opened
up a whole door of like I should look
into that. Why is it like why is this so
difficult to like I could I could
genuinely like tear streaming down my
cheeks think about my neighbor who I've
never really met. They just pull into
their driveway and I see them often
about like, man, I really wish them
well. Like, I hope that they have a
great birthday and I hope that their
family relationships are great and I
hope, oh man, Fourth of July just I hope
they had the best Fourth of July. And
you could think of these things and it's
like real in your body. You're like
releasing all these chemicals of just
I'm really genuinely sending this person
gratitude. Like I really wish them the
best.
>> Yeah.
>> And then
what? All right. think about me
cuz like you know like well like I know
all my stuff you know like I know I know
like well I got I got man bad icky
thoughts sometimes and I don't know if I
deserve do I deserve meta meditate you
know like what what a silly thing to
like get caught up on on sending oursel
um you know the same love that that we
can kind of seamlessly send send to
others but so so that's a whole journey
so I wonder for you Blake was it um did
you have anything similar like where
it's difficult to send yourself love.
>> Yeah, I still I forced myself through
it.
>> Past hard. So, yeah,
>> I'm slowly slowly p pulling that one
off. I'm not even at the point like I
say it and I I can tell it it's just
kind of like there's still a lot of that
coating on me that washes it off
immediately. It's like a beating like
like a rain protector kind of thing, you
know? It's like the water just streams
off. It's like Yeah, it's kind of like
that. It's like I got to wash it some
more. I mean it's really it's great
great technology this this emotional
rainex that we emit.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Exactly. Well, you know and
the the interesting thing is I have a
little picture of of me on my puja table
as a kid
>> and I use that a lot to like build that.
So like when I get up in the morning and
when I go to bed and say good night to
everybody chilling on my puja table, I'm
like uh it's when I growing up uh my
nickname for my family that was
affectionate was Blakey Boy. And so
whenever I want to get in touch with
that child part of myself, I So every
morning it's good good morning Blakey
boy, you know, good night Blakey boy. So
usually when I say like I when I say
that kind of stuff, um I'm I'm thinking
of Blakey boy. And I hope that in
closing the gap between me and Blakey
boy. Uh and and recognizing that that's
a part of my deeper being is just these
experiences, the law unfolding of Blake.
Uh that that that can kind of bring the
now Blake.
>> Yeah.
>> That love.
>> If if you ever write a book, you have to
call it closing the gap between me and
Blakey Boy. That's just like
>> Yeah.
>> present. It's so nice.
>> It's like the sequel to some crazy sad
movie.
Yeah. Yeah. Write some like doom and
gloom first. Write your first book needs
to be like look AI is going to murder
everyone and it's just the truth and
like close the last page and there's no
wishful thinking and then your next book
is just like how to love your internet.
>> Yeah.
>> Just
cuz
that's a pretty apt description of my
life. I think there's a lot of that like
doom and gloom and now I'm in just like
a completely different area of Blakey
boy.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
See, I'm I'm I'm in similar boats, bro.
I um I notice like I spent so much time,
you know, if you get into meditation and
kind of questioning the self, you know,
when I first stumbled into it for me was
uh you know, by necessity. I was very
like I was dealing with just insane
anxiety, depression, just partying too
much. Um just like I I was just I got to
the point, you know, doctors I went to
the doctor and got prescribed
anti-depressants and all these things
and they just everything kept getting
worse and worse and I had this kind of
breaking point of like dude, what the
[__] Like nobody is able to help me. I
got to figure out what is going on here.
So I just went extreme of like not only
what is making me so upset, what is
causing my depression, why am I
suffering, but also just like kept
unwinding to like what is I even like
what is the self that is depressed like
and that opens a whole door of you know
I had like you know some level of
psychosis really by unwinding some of
that stuff but um it was out of
necessity. It was out of um like
you you know we suffer
we suffer so much and I think a lot of
our suffering is like we never really
fully follow the thought like we follow
the thought enough to get stressed out
about it
>> but like if we keep following it and
like really accepting it like we can get
it sounds nihilistic it sounds negative
as we would say but I kept following
thought like what is the self and
suddenly you realize like after some
meditation teachers and books, you're
like, "Oh, [__] The self doesn't
exist." Like, who I thought I was was
suffering. And um you know for anybody
listening I know that sounds maybe like
a little bit of a freaky thought of like
what is the self and and who am I and
all that stuff but there's actually a
lot of freedom in it you know to
recognize that we are kind of a you know
a mastrom of of of patterns and uh
experiences and and happen stance of
we're kind of continuously reacting to
things that happened to us when we were
younger. Um and so
you know
when
when we kind of like are forced to sit
down and
and face and accept like our death like
there there's this saying um in the like
Illusinian mysteries uh uh of like if
you die before you die when you die you
will not die you know and it's kind of
flirting with the Like if you can become
aware of what the ego is and not ego in
the word of like the the cheapening of
like oh that guy's cocky and he's at the
club and he's got you know pukushell
necklaces or whatever kids wear. Um uh
what a stupid sense. Uh uh but like
really of this
like right in between all this love and
this meta and like uh like oh my
neighbor like they're so so precious and
they had a childhood but like in the
same sentence I can go like yeah death
is absolute like we're going to die you
know and it sounds morbid right but it's
actually kind of two sides of the same
coin you can't decouple them um there is
some truth and beauty in kind of
>> in some ways accepting that how
minuscule and and and soft and quick
this whole experience is like like
what a mistake to not be able to find
grace for your parents for like giving
you the tool the only tools they had you
know
>> in this this very minuscule um short
existence that we have we have the gift
of like somebody loving us of somebody
taking care caring of us to the best of
our their ability um and and I think it
it just goes hand in hand. Um I'm trying
to land on a question here for you,
Blake. I guess just like maybe maybe
that that line between acceptance of
kind of our death and our our mortality
and like how does what does that have to
do with meta love and kindness
meditation? Like do you find any
correlations in on your journey between
those you know those?
>> Yeah, that's actually that's actually
pretty poignant. Um that's my inn with
myself actually like to to loving myself
is like paying attention you know I I
thought for many years about death and
uh what that whole trip is about and a
lot of years being scared and taking
very existential um existential views on
that and this idea of like well when
this is it this is it you know Like I
the logical side of me was always just
there thinking like well it's just a
chemical processes and electrical
signals and things are connected in a
certain way and if they're not connected
that way then you know ship of thesis
arguments of like you know if I replace
like how am I still the same person I
was when I was a kid what is the common
thread that's crazy you know
>> and so kind of following all that uh the
thought that I have of dying and being
like, I'm going to miss this. I'm going
to miss Blake. I'm going to miss hanging
out. I'm going to miss all the people
that I have in my life, all these
people. Uh, all the beings that I've
interacted with, animals, stuff like
that. I went on a walk the other day and
I saw a cat and it's like, oh, we're
alive at the same time. Like,
>> how sick.
>> You know, we're connected. Like, oh,
look at you're looking at me, I'm
looking at you, man. Like,
>> this is it.
>> How'd you get into that one? as a way.
Exactly. Yeah. And so recognizing that I
feel that way uh is one of the most
powerful things that have brought me to
a place of being able to even say like,
"Oh, I must love myself." Cuz if I can
sit here and be like, "Oh, this is going
to kind of suck to not do this." Like
when you get past all the like scare,
all the stuff, when you can separate
enough from yourself to be like, oh
yeah, but like when I die, even if I
can't like, okay, I'm not going to know
that I'm it's going to be what it was
like before I was born, but I'm not
going to that sucks. Like right now, I'm
grieving that, you know, that sucks. I
want to be around to do Blake stuff, you
know? Like that is enough for me to like
Yeah. to to just continue to push it, to
continue to like, okay, there's a part
of me in there somewhere in there. I do
love myself somewhere in there. I do see
that. I do really like grab on to that.
So,
>> there's something in there.
>> Yeah. Yeah, there definitely is. There
there's some some through line. I mean,
for me, it was just really it was really
helpful like is because it turned a
continuous scary thought, you know,
someone who's dealing with like suicidal
ideiation, depression, that sort of
thing. you have this kind of like, well,
I guess I'll just kill myself and then
it'll all be over or, you know, I think
as as an artist, I also I've talked
about this on the podcast before, but I
kind of had some weird fantasies around
the 27 Club, too. Like, oh, I'll be
important once they
>> once they they'll check out my art and
see its geneality once I'm dead, you
know? And it's this like it sounds so
silly and tongue and cheek and all these
things, but like that's really where my
mind was back then.
it sounds like this childish like
a lot of ways I think you know it was in
so many ways like make sure you
recognize how important I am and it's
like what like that's that's for you to
like you're already important it's
already being recognized it's kind of
like once you can fall back outside of
your stories and have a relationship
with the greater universe that's like
moving through you it's like that
importance is already there and nobody
has to tell you it and you don't have to
reaffirm yourself like it's fine. Like
exactly who you are is only who you are
and there's nobody else like you. And
that is [__] holy crap. Like like
like zoom out like Yeah. What a trip
indeed.
>> Zoom out.
>> Zoom way out, dude. It's just like what
how precious is is this whole thing. And
and what a what a mistake to
>> make ourselves so small um
as to like you know overlook our own
importance
>> you know
>> like we don't need the big we don't need
the ego importance of like I'm
>> I'm cool and like you see my VIP
wristband I'm I'm with the DJ like it's
not that important but it's like like
you know my my sisters only have one
brother.
>> Yeah. like that important like I
>> like I don't get to choose other sisters
you know and they're frustrating and
they piss me off and it's very difficult
to have a relationship with them but I
love them you know and they're the only
sisters I have and I'm the only brother
I have and that's importance like you
know that's that's the gift I don't get
to change it I don't get to look at
other people with cooler sisters than me
and just like I wish I had cooler
sisters and they they don't get to like
wish they had a like I'm the brother
they have
>> you know and and there's um
>> meditation is constantly facing the
truth, right? You know,
>> yes. It's like how do we how do we
continually
not try to change our stories, but
recognize that we're telling a story
>> and uh allow the preciousness that's
already there to to really be there or
or something like that.
>> Yeah. I I mean I mentioned this just
briefly a little bit ago, but that
lawfulness of people that that
perspective shift for me has changed so
much in the way that like the compassion
that I can hold for people doing things
that I don't like that are doing uh
their things like just looking at it as
like you know I as a mathematician when
I do my algebra junk that I do and Like
one of the reasons that I started loving
mathematics is I was on the train and I
was like doing some math homework and uh
I got like to the end of a proof that I
was writing and you know I got to the
end and I was like and then I looked at
it and I laughed and I was like oh I
didn't see how I was going to get from
here to here but I got there you know
and like there's
>> something about
that like I don't get mad about that.
It's not like when I write a proof and
then something's at the end I'm like
>> really you know or like halfway through
it I'm like this is stupid. Why are they
like this?
>> Why is reality like this? This is so
annoying.
>> Why why is this you know why is this
orbit this way? Why is the uler Yeah.
Why is the oiler number of this thing
you know whatever? Yeah.
>> What is makes me angry.
>> Yeah. Exactly. And so having that
perspective of like, well, people can
work that way, too. Like I can I can
just think about it as like the apple
falling from the tree. No one's going to
be like, what the why' it do that?
Who the hell fall? Yeah.
>> And and also, [__] you, Apple, man.
>> I wanted you on that tree for a little
bit longer. Like, no. And like and
Ramdas says that thing often about like
you know being being angry often is a is
a conduit of like this if I was God this
isn't how the world would be
and I love that cuz like every time I
get angry then I think like am I angry
like not because if I was in charge this
would be different or is this like
something else you know and often it's
like
>> I'm angry because if I was in charge no
one would drive in traffic like this you
know If I was in charge, there would be
no traffic.
>> Dude, I love that.
>> So, it takes a different perspective of
it. And bringing it back to meditation
is a great place to explore that law
unfolding in your head.
>> Bro, I think I'm going to use that. I I
haven't heard it worded in such a way.
If I was angry or or if I was in charge,
I'd be angry about this thing. Like, if
if I were in charge, I'd wish to
>> Yeah. When you get angry, it's like,
yeah, I'm I'm mad because like I'm, you
know, splitting up with somebody. It's
like, oh, I'm mad because if I was in
charge, we would be together. If I could
control everything about this, this this
is how it would work.
>> But it's not. And so what are you going
to do?
>> Yeah,
>> it's not. And what are you going to do,
you know?
>> And so then think about the perfection
of, oh, we're breaking up a
>> I don't know what we're doing. Why are
we
>> Yeah. Yeah. We're we're really just
along for the ride. um you know and and
I think it is this constant balance and
again it's not it is this really precise
constant practice of always opening up
to
>> because in that moment when someone's
breaking up with you it's hard to go ah
so
>> so you don't love me anymore right you
know and like cuz really what's
happening is is is you're devastated and
you now have to mourn and and and you're
upset and all these things but it's um
you know I'll tell you when I
>> I was towards the end of my getting my
meditation teacher certification and I
got I got dumped and I was dating this
girl and it was like we were only
together for like four months but it was
just this freaking whirlwind of like
like I mean it sounds really silly now
but we're we're very much like
>> oh it it was love like man on on our
first date we were both just like is
this love at first sight like we're both
just so intense man I was just so like
at like the poet in me was like
>> yes I was just bro I was just level 100
at all. Like I'd wake up just so excited
to text this individual. Like we were
just so deep in it, you know.
>> Um
>> but like you know and then we split up
and I was like uh man it was like on a
Thursday and the next day I had to wake
up and like do my like
>> you know like 10-hour meditation teacher
certification and I'm just ugly crying
here in my apartment like how do I like
how do I what would I you know what what
advice do I give myself? like it and
it's just so frustrating, right? And
it's it's so funny because like
>> it pissed me off and I had to feel being
pissed off, but like even in the middle
of me I was so sad, just so upset and
mourning the loss of all these futures.
We had just I brought her back to to
Kelso, our hometown, and she had met my
family and friends and I thought it all
went so great. And I have all these
crazy fantasies of like what the future
looks like in the next few years with
this individual. And I had to just like
I'm mourning all that and I'm still like
all right I got to be a meditation
teacher tomorrow
dude. Um, and you know, and and so what
I really had to do was like I had to
show up to a meditation teacher class
with puffy eyes and and and and that was
the truth of it, you know. It's like,
as much as it hurt so bad and it was
very real and I'm mourning all these
things, it was also like what a this is
frustrating to admit, but what a gift
that I just got to fall in love with
someone for 4 months. Like dude, holy
[__] Like what a gift. God damn it.
This gift sucks, you know? But like what
a what a gift, you know. Um and and it's
uh it's it's that constant push and
pull, you know, and and now now what do
I get, Blake, is I get this,
>> you know, whatever I end up doing with
this meditation teacher, this this cool
piece of paper that I get to connect and
and hopefully teach people new new time,
new beginners, how to how to how to deal
with their version of that. I get this
lifelong story of like, hey, you know,
I'm not trying to come across as some
dude who is like in the middle of my my
teacher certification, the stuff I'm
talking about, like how I'm like
teaching you right now, I was balling my
eyes out during it. So like I'm not some
zen, peaceful, perfect. I'm just a a
sticky, gross, stinky human just like
you. Um and and here it is, you know,
here here's my experience. What what's
yours like? you know. So, um yeah, I
meditation is this constant like
allowing those gushy wonderful
beautiful, you know, liquidy yokeky
feelings to happen, but also like the
>> the sharp edges of metal that life is,
you know, and like sometimes you
sometimes your your arm gets cut on that
sharp metal and it hurts, you know, and
that's still life. Absolutely.
>> That's still life, too, you know.
>> Yeah. And you need somebody in your
corner saying, "The moments I feel most
connected with you are when you cut
yourself on those sharp corners."
>> Yeah.
>> You know,
>> like you're okay when you're bleeding.
>> Yeah.
>> Like you're crying right now. That's
okay.
>> You're not wrong. Yeah.
>> It's it's it's a beautiful thing for
sure. And meditation definitely helps
cultivate that in yourself.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Um Okay. So, how did
you I think I barreled through through
the question that I asked earlier. How
did you very first get into medit med
meditation? Like so you said like
something with Ramdas first clicked with
you but like even listening to Ramdas in
the first place to me is like that's
that's an a step in in towards
meditation. So like I mean maybe even
let's take a step back farther. How did
you kind of first get into spirituality?
Like was that a profound move for you
shift for you?
>> Yeah, I think so. Uh
I don't I don't even know man. It's uh I
was very averse to it for a long time.
I've been very like frankly critical of
>> astrology and anything woo woo I was
like nopem don't believe it and just in
exploring myself and you know there
there's been a few times in my life
where I've witnessed my authentic self
showing up to things and that
it's like
too heavy. Like it's it's scary for me.
It was It's a lot less now, but it was,
you know, very scary. It's like, "Oh,
okay. All right. I better chill out. I
better not Blakey Boy is not allowed
here." like you know or like uh I don't
I don't know if this is true so I'm just
you know even even if I feel it like you
know and I was very staunchly like this
doesn't make sense so it can't be true
it has to make sense and so I just
continually like pushed back against
everything I was always trying to look
about like why are things not the way
that they are
>> and
going through mathematics you learn
different ways to prove things and you
learned that like it's a lot harder to
prove that something is a certain way
than it is to prove that something is
not any other way and you get like stuck
in these kind of like traps of how am I
going to perceive the world and in a lot
of ways doing all of that mathematics
it changed so much about how I perceived
truth and value and uh what anything
meant anywhere you know for anything and
so I started I actually gave the Beatles
a listen. I was like, "All right, maybe,
you know, everybody likes the Beatles.
Maybe I should listen to something more
than just some of the White Album." So,
I like listened to the White Album. And
now I have uh the Magical Mystery Tour
back there on my wall. It's been a long
journey, but um I think really actually
just getting into the Beatles. I was
like, well, I mean, they kind of got
into psychedelics.
They did. Paul McCartney probably uh
meditates, you know. My dad meditated.
Maybe I should just like try it. And I
was like, I have no idea what to do with
it. I think I looked up some YouTube
videos that were like, how do you
meditate? Which is where I learned like,
oh, you got to be, you know, focus like
live here
for a minute, you know, focus there, all
that stuff. So, I think that's where
like yeah, I initially initially got
into it is I just had these
transformative experiences that kept
slowly opening me up to things that
weren't necessarily black and white.
>> Yeah. Okay, man. I really want to learn
more about
your view on mathematics. Um, I find
when we were kids,
I always found
um numbers like they didn't hit for me.
I I didn't somehow someway this I'm
gonna I'm about to place a fault on one
of my teachers, but somehow nobody
>> I I didn't hear the magic of math like
like now that I'm older and I like I
listen to mathematicians talk like I
really do you know Eric Weinstein
>> Mhm.
>> Yeah. I um I I I really really like um
listening to him talk about like physics
and stuff, but um just like hearing
people like that who are lit up by math
um talk about it and talk, you know, you
learn about like the Fibonacci sequence
and you learn about like just these
super interesting like mind-blowing
facts about the earth that like only
math can bring us to and uh but I didn't
have that until till I was older. So um
I think
tell me and and you could take this
question wherever um in and mold it into
how it works for your explanation. How
is math beautiful?
>> Yeah.
The the cliche answer is that it's a
language, right?
um
and and that it describes uh so much
about what's going on around us, right?
So it's like, "Oh, it's beautiful
because math is a language and we can
use it to describe ideas." Oh, that's
like what most people say or like uh
they they talk a lot about like the
application like, "Oh, math is beautiful
because it's deeply integrated into
everything we do." And those are all
true. But for me, I think math is
beautiful because
it is
and not even that it is beautiful
because math math to me is
a
method of beauty. Like it's not
beautiful itself, but there's so much
beauty and elegance inside of
mathematics that goes so far beyond just
equations. that goes so far like I told
you about the the comedy that I saw in
it, you know, and uh there's like it's
it's like a form of poetry in a lot of
ways. Not necessarily in terms of like
it being a language as much as poetry is
a language, right? Um I I feel like math
often gets overlooked because it feels
very strenuous. It feels very like
arduous maybe where where it's like oh
well I have to do so much and it's like
what does the you know letters have to
do with anything but once you get to it
there's like a certain point where
you know you may not even have an equal
sign you're just kind of like goofing
around with stuff like
in my later math classes I would often
joke that like I'm going into like we I
took this advanced algebra class this is
on a topic called group theory which is
just it's a type of number theory. You
have groups, rings and fields. And uh
this was in group theory. And we one of
my classes we actually like did crafts
like we took like cuz you think about
how many different ways you can like
flip a triangle.
>> And like if you if you flip it if you
turn it it's completely different than
if you like rotate it, right? Like those
are flipping and rotating are two
different things. And so we had to like
build these triangles that had like
numbers on them and then we found a way
to describe that mathematically given
the numbers that are on like the corners
of like how are we going to rotate this?
And that was that's like the beauty to
me. It's like yeah there's like a
physical start of something but math
shows you that just because something
has a physical correlary just because we
can connect it to something physical.
This is a completely like out in the
like you don't it doesn't have to be
that way like it doesn't have to be
connected to anything physical for it to
be a thing that like fits in our rule
book. So it's a way to explore things
that are metaphysical in a way that
allows people to share those ideas much
in the same way that you and I might
talk about meditation which is something
you can't measure.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> I I love thinking about it as as a
language. I you know sure sure it's a
bit cliche but I do think that that is
actually a very profound way to approach
math is is seeing it as a language.
>> Um
>> I
do you think math is something that
>> you know a lot of my questions are kind
of like if you're an alien watching what
the humans what those weird apes are
doing. Um
>> do you think humans discovered math or
invented math or neither? Oh yeah, this
question. Yeah, I love I love when this
question comes up. It's
discovered or invented.
I think it's a method of discovery.
Yeah. But I think we also
I think we're inventing tools to
discover mathematics. So, we're like
it's it's like a like a like snail a
snake eating its tail.
>> It's like I think yeah, we're
discovering a lot, but every discovery
just builds new tools to be able to
discover more. So, it's kind of weird.
You you think about like, oh, some of
this stuff people couldn't even have
thought of, you know, a thousand years
ago. And some of that is true because
some of it doesn't have any kind of
connection to anything physical, you
know, like there's a famous uh example
or there's a famous mathematician called
Gwa and uh he was this French
mathematician who was like
all over the French Revolution and like
super like politically charged and
motivated and he's like 20 years old and
he's like writing mathematics that
people are like What the where did you
even get this? You know, it's like he's
a conduit of God or something. Like he's
writing and so he's like writing this
stuff down. He's in jail because of all
of his political junk that he's doing
and he has a duel that he's going to go
do. And so he like writes down this
whole opus of like beautiful math. He's
got his own
field of math. It's called Galwa theory
and it's all about the lee groups and
like different it's very related to
group theory like I was talking about
and all this stuff. So anyways it's it's
about symmetry and um rational roots of
polomials. So it's it's like this like
very abstract like you can't look at
this stuff. You have to describe based
on maybe what you're thinking what you
can try and visualize maybe. He writes
all this stuff down before his duel. He
gives it to his brother and he's like,
"If something was to happen to me, just
give this to the college." And then he
goes out and gets shot and dies at 22.
>> And those notes that he wrote get put in
the college that told him he couldn't go
there. And they take it and they're
like, "Oh my god, this is amazing. This
is so crazy and beautiful." And he's
dead at that point. But he's opening up
this entire field of mathematics that
now hundreds of years later is still
happening. It's still being developed
on. So in a way, yes, he discovered it,
but also invented it, if that makes
sense.
>> Yeah. Like
only he could have
invented it, but
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. It's like this complicated. It It
really makes you I always default to
like like where do ideas really come
from? Like what is an idea? Um, but it I
I feel like there is these uh you know,
wonder kids, especially in math. Like,
uh, you know, I've heard Eric Weinstein
talk about a cup. I cannot remember any
of their names. Go figure. But um he's
talked about how he's been in classes
where he sits there's some young young
like person in the back and there's you
know a room full of mathematicians in in
in physicists and all these you know
self self-appointed smart people and uh
one person will ask a question or it's
their turn to give you know a 10 20
minute lecture whatever and like these
lifelong mathematicians are leaning over
going I have no idea what he's talking
about you know like
>> in that that is just so profound and
it's very interesting like kind of the
savant nature of some of these skills
like um that I I think about that that
show numbers um
>> uh like like that you know the main
character
>> I know I think we watched it in high
school actually I I it's one of those
that I always whenever I think of it I
go man I want to rewatch that I wonder
if I would enjoy it as much but um like
he clearly has some you know at least in
the in the show anyway he has like some
savant level mathematician um stuff and
he's able to you know kind of like you
described he's like can describe crimes
>> in these like intricate ways and like
here's what the murder's motivational
motivation was and they interacted with
this person and I don't know that that
show kind of uh blew my mind but so do
you think that as much as you know we
have you know the Gandhi and um you know
we have these kind of like art we live
in such a world where believe it or not,
it could be up to you, but there is
these sants that are born like oh that's
the next Buddha or that's the you know
this person at 5 years old started
showing signs of like knowing some [__]
that he shouldn't know and so now we
like put him in robes and we worship him
and we whatever you know we listen to
what he has to say for the rest of his
life. I think there's something a bit
magical about like math skills sometimes
even like
>> there's there's people born with some of
these insane ways of seeing the world.
It's like like you said like
>> do they have some sort of language that
they're born kind of
>> being fluent in and it's just a matter
of them being able to like
>> express it in somehow in in their lives?
I don't know. What do you think about
that? Do you think there's like people
born with with specific skills um in in
math and in science and those sorts of
things?
>> I think if you had asked me this
question five years ago, I'd be like,
"No,
no, there's there's something that
happened in their life that, you know,
led them to have that ability." Now I'm
much more open to the idea that yeah,
somebody probably uh some of these
people probably just their brains get
wired
from the moment they were conceived to,
you know, produce these things. It's
one of those mathematicians is living
right now named Terry Tao who at like
eight was like PhD level mathematics.
>> Wow.
>> You know, crazy stuff. He's a he's a
very very very well-known he's got a
beautiful blog about mathematics where
he answer asks questions and like muses
about mathematics. He's a super cool
guy. He's he's written a lot of great um
analysis uh textbooks and things like
that. But uh Terry Tao is definitely one
of those people. Um further back there's
Emmy Noithther who discovered an entire
theory around um rings like a type of
ring uh in ring theory mathematical
object and she worked closely with
Einstein actually and she was one of the
first women appointed at uh some German
institute or something that that
Einstein was on cuz she had applied and
she was working um doing all this stuff
and she um she like was finishing her
PhD and doing all this stuff but like
everybody was kind of like hush hush
about it. They were all like, "Well, you
know, women, yeah, all that stuff that
they did back then." And Einstein was
kind of like, "You guys are stupid. What
are you doing?" And they were like, "Oh,
well, if Einstein's cool with it, then
so she got like appointed and she
started like teaching and all that
stuff." But she's another person where
like from an early age she was
apparently able to visualize the fourth
dimension, which is mind-boggling to me.
I don't know if you've ever read the
book Flatland.
I
>> I've heard of I know of it, but I
haven't read it.
>> Yeah. It's like, you know, if you're a
two-dimensional being, imagining the
third dimension is crazy. Like, you
couldn't imagine it. And so, like,
thinking of us in the third dimension
and her being able to think about things
and being like, "Oh, yeah. Well, you
know what? The fourth dimension, the
geometry works like this." And it's
like,
>> she has the math to back it up and
stuff. And it's like that was intuitive.
She intuited it. And 5 years ago, I'd
say there's no such thing as intuition.
>> Uhhuh. And somehow this lady lives on a
complete separate plane than us and
she's able to communicate like how it
makes sense to us on her
>> way before with no training. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Um Okay. So where what do
you think
you know there's a in kind of like the
math and physics community.
I kind of lean into I'm I'm always
wanting to think of a ways like I have
like this Einstein poster behind thing
behind me. It's a I I didn't paint it. I
bought it from like Fred Meyer, but um I
I did paint so I'm such an artist. Uh I
painted sorry on it in like
>> what's funny is like it's deep to me.
It's not deep, but it's deep to me
because like my where I come from as an
artist, like I love breaking [__] I
love bulldozing [__] I love like like
>> you know I I think like our
Einstein gave us these equations and
we're like continually working on these
equations and we're continually like
going that way and I think where we're
at with like quantum physics and stuff
you know again like Eric Weinstein
explains a lot of kind of what what he
thinks a lot of that and I think maybe I
I just kind of parody a lot of his his
opinions in some ways um but like
to me I feel that we're more on the
cuffs as a species of like discovering a
new way like I don't think that our next
big explosion in understanding who and
what we are and like new new dimensions
and like whatever the future of
technology and um um intelligence is you
know 20 50 100 200 years I don't
specifically think that it's only in the
direction that Einstein sent us and I
also don't think that it's in like this
like quantum stranges this quantum
weirdness like we keep
Like there there's a lot of you know on
YouTube and books and all these things
like I think we keep having these like
quantum smoking guns that people are
like oh this is how reality works and
like it's actually many worlds and and
at any point you're pulling from uh
infinite number of worlds to make this
reality and like we keep like sitting
back all right we figured it out like
and and and to me I'm just like I what
is the there's not that's not an end.
>> Um I hope this makes sense to you but um
>> I I don't know. So what what do you I'm
more prone to think that our next
advancements
are not so much in the realm of quantum
physics but more so and not so much in
the realm of physics at all actually for
that matter. I don't think that what's
new for humans and in consciousness is
let's get to Mars and we'll figure it
out. Let's see what's beyond Mars. I
don't think it's in time and space
necessarily. I think that it's more in
the weirdness of like psychedelics where
like you unfold you you discover these
other realms that are kind of all right
here in some ways. So um another
impossible question for you Blake but
what do you so what do you think about
like the future of math and physics over
the course of like 50 200 500 years? Are
we facing the right direction? Are we
going to get into some weird directions?
Is it still math? Is it not math?
>> I'll hand that to you. There's an
impossible question.
I don't know if it's impossible, but
it's definitely an interesting question
for sure. Um,
where are we going? I'm I'm immediately
thinking about uh Ray Kerszswwell. Do
you know who that is?
>> Yes. Yeah.
>> Yeah. The father of AI. Um, did as a
sidebar really quick, did you know that
he has all of his father's journals? His
father was like a prolific journaler and
he's like wrote every day and he's got
like a whole room full of his father's
journals from like 70 years of
journaling.
>> That's so sick. I didn't know that. No,
>> he was originally going to like trying
to put it digitize it and then rebuild
his father
>> digitally from all of this thing, which
is absolutely insane and super cool.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
But
I think about him and the um the
exponential rate of technology growth.
Exponential rate of growth in
technology. So you know I feel like
everybody's maybe I've just said it a
million times over the many years. Uh
but uh you know you think about like the
difference between iPhone 1 2 3 and then
like all the way up like it's the fact
that we had no iPhone 20 years ago and
then wait was the first iPhone 2005
maybe
>> 2007 I think 2007
>> somewhere around there. Yeah. So
anyways, we did we didn't have an and
then the iPhone that we have today is
like better than most people's cameras
and like you know more powerful than
anything that's ever and then you know
the amount of time it took for us to
just get from like the computer that put
us on the moon to uh you know Windows
with like a you know and then we got on
trackpads and you know all that kind of
stuff. So, and then we got iPads and
like a lot of people are using their
computers uh just straight off of an
iPad, you know, where they have like a
detachable keyboard and it's like, you
know, it's very very futuristic, very
very weird. Nobody had any idea that
that's where we were going with it. I
mean, I'm sure there's some freaky
people that were like in 100. I think
there's some like mo books from like the
20s where they talked about like a
future where people touch the screen and
stuff like that. But uh yeah, I think
that there's
an endless,
how do I want to say this? I think that
that technology is changing so fast now
that
in a lot of ways that you're talking
about, you know, physics and math not
being like the future or like whatever
that's going to do, especially with, you
know, in regards to human consciousness.
Um that's because so much of that is
just happening all at once, right? Um
with LLMs and AI, we can do protein
folding and we can figure out things for
drugs in, you know, fractions of a time
that it used to take 10 years to figure
out how to do one drug or whatever or
like figure out uh anything about
viruses or anything about the human
genome or anything like that. Like the
computation power that we have today is
insane. Just in, you know, my MacBook or
in our in our phones. Even just like the
computation power inside of this to do
things inside the one that's in my ear
is crazy. I'm sure it's, you know,
better than whatever they put us on the
moon with,
>> you know, and it's all it does is just
put sound in my ear, you know. So, um,
you're right. I think that society
probably will will do like a a circle,
you know, the the flat disc of time
where pretty soon it'll be too intense
and there will be a a I think our co
conscious as a consciousness as a as
our consciousness as humanity is being
offloaded into the cyber realm slowly
like bit by bit. there's pieces of you
like you've you've always done the Jacob
from the internet thing like you're
tuned into that like that idea that
there's a separate consciousness that's
happening online that's happening
outside of us as humans and we're slowly
like so much is happening there that's
not anywhere in the real world
>> you know there's stuff that I've said to
people that if all the power went out in
the world it just wouldn't exist anymore
you know, I mean, it exists, but like
you couldn't get to it. You couldn't
experience it. You couldn't see it.
>> And in a lot of ways, that's completely
the same. Like, it's not like a written
wrote note that's been given to somebody
where it's this exists until it doesn't.
It's
>> where is it? Yeah. Yeah.
>> So I think that as that goes, human
consciousness from what we actually are,
the meditation, all the cool stuff that
is like being human, going offline, all
that kind of stuff. That's probably what
we'll get more into.
>> We'll let cyber us do all the physics,
all the math, all the other junk, and
then we'll just get to sit around and
>> Wow, what a
>> I love that thought, man. And it's like
um
like it it reminds me of that um you
know like Alan Watts kind of talks about
how we're all just kind of like a a
splinter of God. Like it was one big
thing and then it's all we're all just
like splinters of of like the one big
thing having experiences just for the
fun of it sort of thing. And like now we
kind of, you know, for lack of a better
sense, have the power to fraction
ourselves once more
>> and like create a like I always called
the, you know, with the Jacob from the
internet thing. I
I really think about our internet selves
and just being connected to the internet
and the fact that at any moment I could
be, you know, I'm talking with my
friend, but like at any moment I could
have I could be pulled by this like
vortex, this like dirt tunnel that's not
a dirt tunnel. It's like this digital
dirt tunnel to like like right now I
could just off airplane mode and like
just see a live stream of China.
>> Yep.
>> Holy [__] dude. Like you know what I
mean? like this is a magic box into like
other places in the universe. But it's
um I wonder how much not only that it it
fractions us and like who we are, you
know, where we're fractioning ourselves
before we fully understand what we are.
And I I don't know if that's a bug or
feature, but um
>> yeah,
>> like I always kind of call it this
second ego in a way, you know, and and I
think that, you know, I see it a lot and
I I really love like the spiritual
community. I love like the like the airy
like the the rock girls in in the
crystals and the like the enchanting.
Like I love like the very like woo woo
side of things, but at the same time I
see how much it's like oh
>> y'all are being tricked by like a second
ego. Like you think you are this
spiritual like blah blah blah cuz you
have so many followers online and then
you like act that out. But like get rid
of your phone for six months and you're
going to have a [__] identity crisis
of like who you are because in your
day-to-day life without the phone
fueling things like you know you you
still deal with like patterns like when
you go talk to your mom and try to bring
her to to her doctor's appointment you
know like how spiritual are you really
when your when your mom's triggering
you? Um you know so I I I don't know. I
really wonder about like I think it's so
fascinating to continue with technology
and like we're going to just keep coming
up with edges of like we can't ignore
the question of who and what we are like
it's part of the human experience and
it's not a question to be answered in
like cool all right next it's a
continuous like we're always you know
everyone's experience is like
discovering who they are and also
discovering who who who they are not so
Yeah, I don't know. I I I love to think
about the future of technology and like
how it really intricately
um you know, it exposes us to who who we
are on on a continuous level and who
we're not, right? You know, so
>> yeah,
>> it's it's it's interesting
>> limitations.
>> Yeah, it's interesting to think of where
we're going, right? It's
>> Yeah,
>> I would love for math and physics to
kind of open up in a direction that we
could never predict at this point.
I think that there's this it reminds me
of um a Ram DS talk where he's because a
lot of times technology gets very doom
and gloom, right? Like people like you
were kind of saying like there's a lot
of Yeah. Anyways, um Ron Doss is talking
about talking with that uh
famous conservationist. I can't remember
what his name was. Um, but he was
talking about like how do you like keep
it together? You know, like the the ppm
on CO2 is going crazy. Like forests are
getting cut down. Like what do you do?
And he's like, you know, wasn't that
long ago that we crawled out of the
ocean, you know? Don't don't write
humans off so quick.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Exactly. So I think that you
with our in a lot of ways we're cursed
and blessed with short lives, but it
often makes us makes it hard to think
about what I mean in 2 million years,
what are we going to
>> Yeah. Like God, I I that's such such a
perfect point, too. Imagine like we're
in the ocean and we're these [__]
tadpoles swimming around and we're like,
what are we going to do, dude? And like
>> we freaking Yeah, dude. Crawl up on the
beach and then it's like a whole new,
you know, oh, oxygen. Like that's
>> trees. Like there's stuff up here.
>> Yeah. We are completely not disconnected
from the trees and now we are at one
more than we were in the first place.
Yeah. Wouldn't that be fascinating if
like,
>> you know, on on the front page of CNN or
or Fox News or NBC or any of these, you
know, for whatever reason, this analogy,
this the news networks who are get
telling us what we are, but um like new
discovery that we can pop out of this
dimension completely and it's a whole
new reality reality out there.
>> Yeah.
>> We just lose interest in this reality
because there's a new dimension being
unfolded.
>> Oh my. You know what? That actually is
such a great Have you I I want to ask
you just I've been thinking about this
for months. The um CIA like uh
decl
classified some stuff that they did on
on psychedelic work. Uh not psychedelics
but like you know uh
what are they parasychology or something
like that?
>> And and have you heard of it's project
Stargate? There's the OpenAI one that's
like famous right now because it's a
bunch of money, but uh then there's this
other one called Project Stargate. Have
you heard of it?
>> Um I I've heard of it, but you'll have
to indulge me. You have to
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I will. I will. So,
the government taught these uh CIA
agents how to astral project
>> and they had them do experiments with
it. And according to this report, very
thorough, fascinating read,
they did it and they met beings and like
could go into other rooms and see what
was written on cards and stuff and like
report back like, "Oh yeah, it says
this." Cuz they were trying to use it
like all governments to do some warfare
stuff, you know, thinking, "Oh, we can
travel." But then it got like too
sketchy cuz they kept running into
things that they didn't know how to deal
with. whether or not that was, you know,
them bringing their karma along with
them or whatever, you know, you can
argue, but
>> but I to that exact point if
>> it seems like maybe we can I would it
would be interesting if we as a society
could just astral project and like have
a dance party, you know?
>> Yeah, dude. Yeah. I mean, imagine that
instead of like me me saying, "Hey, I'm
going live on Twitch." It's like, "Hey,
I'm going live uh at this place that I
made up in my head. You guys can come
on. Come on in. Yeah, ask project and
come on over,
>> bro. How sick is that though to really
think about? Like, have you heard of the
telepathy tapes? Have you heard of this
phenomenon? Oh my word, dude. So, it's
this this like
>> 10 part maybe six part uh podcast
series, but it's like an audio
documentary essentially this this lady
um K K K K K K K K K K K K K K K K K K K
K K K K K K K K K K K K K K K K K K K K
K K
something, K K K K K K K K K K K K K K K
K K K K K K something. Um but
essentially she discovered and she went
and like traveled all these places,
interviewed the kids, interviewed their
parents. Essentially, there's a
phenomenon worldwide, and this is like
thousands and thousands of people like
proof. We did the science, we like
filmed it, we made sure it's like the
the the correct boundaries are set in
place to make it actually a scientific
study, these sorts of things. But
essentially,
uh, mute or nonverbal autistic young
people
>> are able to telepathically communicate.
Um, we discovered it at the beginning.
So the this podcast series goes into at
the beginning it lays out kind of um how
there's kind of this like unison dance
with like these mute kids and their
parents like the person they're the
closest to. And they did those sorts of
research studies where like you know the
parent goes in the other room. The
parent is thinking of a certain object
or a number and the kid is in the other
room like not able to talk but they're
like able to write it out or like they
can spell with um
>> I forget what they call but like they
have little numbers and letters they
point to
>> and consistently they have all these
different studies and tests where it
shows that somehow someway the kid is
reading the mind of the adult in the
other room whether it's their teacher,
their parent, whatever. So like that in
itself is wow mind-blowing right? But it
keeps piling on these telepathy tapes.
Um, I urge anybody listening to check
these out. Such a fascinating listen and
they're just really well done as an
audio documentary. They have this place
place called The Hill.
>> And this place we discovered. Yeah. The
Hill. And it is a
telepathic chat room that these these
non-verbal kids they like just kind of
casually mentioned. In my opinion, this
is kind of how it went across. casually
mention like, "Oh, yeah, I'll see you on
the hill later." Like, "What?" And so
nonverbal kids. So, like I say, I'm in
Washington State and I'm a non-verbal
like a 12-year-old kid. I don't talk,
but I go to this place in my room where
I get under the covers and I put
blankets over my head
>> and I go to the hill and I talk with my
friend uh Francis who lives in Virginia.
I've never met Francis in my entire
life.
>> I don't know this person exists. I don't
have they're not my friend online, but I
talked to this person named Francis at
the Hill and then these people from the
telepathy tapes, they go and they meet
Francis and they're like, "Oh, Steve,
yeah, who lives in Washington? Yeah, we
talked together on the hill." So,
there's a bunch of these like
>> these instances of these things that
these people are saying are happening or
these non-verbal autistic kids are
saying or communicating in some their
ways that like, yes, I know this person.
I meet this person. Oh, I go and hang
out with him on the hill. This place.
Oh, you don't know about the hill?
That's just a place we go in our minds
and talk with our friends.
>> Um,
>> yeah.
>> But anyway, that that's so that's kind
of like, you know, there's a a bunch of
other cool little like tips and tricks
that go along with this whole telepathy
tapes thing. But, um, I mean, it's we're
at this point where this is, you know,
less than six months ago, this was like
a very popular podcast. And so, it's
kind of like what what do we do?
Like we have these we close I can't we
call them truths like this is a true
thing I we have some scientific research
studies that you know placebo or not
these people are able to I I don't know
how else you get to the point where
someone in a different state is
communicating non-verbally with this
other individual and can confirm things
that like they're not texting they're
not they don't have walkie-talkies like
all right tell these suckers that like
I'm holding up three red triangles you
know
>> um so I don't know like like What's
crazy is we seem to be discovering more
about reality at this amplified rate.
>> And what
like where what is that smoking gun?
What is that like thing that we
discovered? When does it start changing
our reality? Cuz to me,
>> we make this discovery.
>> Okay, why don't we start studying like
is it just nonverbal people who can do
this? Is this something that if we train
all young individuals to do, they can go
to this place called the hill? Is there
more information there? Um like like how
fascinating is that? This stuff that we
discover in meditation, in these
telepathic realms, in um these other
realms, these other spaces, these liinal
places, what do we do with the
information that we discover there and
bring it back? Like we're like, "Hey, we
have this golden egg of truth." like it.
How how fascinating, you know,
>> man, we're too we're too busy being
somebody, right?
Everybody's too busy be I'm not going to
go check out the hill because I have to,
you know, I have to make more money so I
can buy a cuz I'm, you know, the guy who
has the sports car in my neighborhood.
>> I'm an important person.
>> Yep. Yep. Or I'm too busy, you know,
doing just whatever uh whatever it might
even be. Just trying to survive. But
that's also just a function of people
not people being too busy being somebody
to like recognize that you always get
higher when you're with someone else,
you know? It's not it's not something
that we should be isolating people about
or anything like that.
>> Yeah.
>> So, it's it's it's it's
like it's a bummer. Like, you're you're
right. You're on it. You know, I want to
go to the hill. Let's do it.
>> Yeah.
>> Why not? You know, it's it's a funny
middle ground of being a human too,
right? Of
>> Yeah.
>> You know, like Ram Das would say, it's
always been my favorite of, you know,
always remember your Buddha nature and
your social security number.
>> We are [__] we're right in the we're
we're right in the middle of all of it.
Like you could have your
>> like the telepathy taste that's all cool
but like you're still in a biological
meat suit that like needs to eat food
tonight at 5:00 p.m. like you know.
Yeah. So like somehow we are in this
insane experience, this insane like what
it is to be human is we have these
survival things and we have this
knowledge of how we got to where we are
and like
>> you know we had to we crawled out of the
water somehow or something and we grew
wings or something and we started having
opposable thumbs or something. But also
we have these thoughts about being all
that is and we could close our eyes and
talk to people who are in different
physical locations. What you know that's
paradox. You know it's it's really that
is one of the more spiritual words in my
opinion is is paradox. Somehow we're
right smack dab in the middle of
>> um you know I went to um
>> I went to the transcendental meditation
like university um is in Fairfield, Iowa
and it's um I went like I stayed on
their campus for a few days and I went I
was drinking the Kool-Aid man and I
almost joined their cult and it was
awesome. Um and I I it's a joke when I
call it a cult. A lot of a lot of people
call it cult. It's really a lovely I had
a wonderful experience like cult or not
I thought it was [__] awesome. Um but
we were on the bus and um I was in a
place with my spiritual experience where
I had just had like some kind of
profound like chance encounters with
people who talked to me about God and
they like gave me encouragement to go on
this trip. And so I was on this like
weird cloud9 um like everything just
made sense like the physical made sense
with the metaphysical.
>> And we're on this bus and there's a lot
of people who are like really into that.
They're like discovering like oh wow I'm
I'm at one with all that is and like we
are consciousness itself and like you do
this meditation where you do this mantra
on repeat with transcendental meditation
and the the mantra
>> you kind of like the mantra keeps going
up here in your mind and you kind of
like settle your experience into this
like
>> like going down below and you're kind of
in this like
>> you know one consciousness you feel you
are the ocean you're not identifying ing
with the waves, whatever. It's it's a
wonderfully blissful experience for
most. Um, but you're doing that for
months on end, twice a day, 20 minutes a
day with transcendental meditation.
>> And then you're trying to like you're
experiencing being one with all that is.
And then you're
you're also like trying to pay the bills
and do your dishes and like trying to
find this this balance in between. So
we're on this bus and people were having
kind of like that freakout experience of
like, whoa. You know, we keep having
these conversations and we go and we
listen to these cool teachers at this
university and they tell us that we're
all one consciousness. And like when
you're listening to it, you're nodding
your head like, "Wow, this is this cuz
when a lot you're listening to a lot of
the spiritual stuff, it feels like a
remembering. It doesn't feel like
someone's telling you new info about
yourself." You're like, "That's that's
true." It doesn't negate all this stuff
that also feels very true, but like I
can't deny that what you're saying feels
like I guess I kind of am all one with
that is um
>> and uh it was just this balance of you
know I'm telling these people these this
emphasis on this word paradox of like
what you're saying is true but like I
noticed like we get kind of freaked out
about it but like somehow we're both
we're all of that. we are this
everything, but we're still on this bus
right now and like it's the end of the
day and we've all been learning and
we're also kind of getting a little bit
tired, right? Like we're so excited
about this. Like we're on people who are
on the spiritual realm and there's
people who are riding high and they're
all vibing out and they I could talk
about, you know, God and the Buddha and
they know what I'm talking about and
that's so stellar.
>> But like also like if you you know like
I'm I'm allergic to gluten. If I eat
gluten, I'm still going to have like a
whole gassy night. You know what I mean?
I'm one with all that is, but I still
have a butt that farts. Damn.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Um, you know, so I um I don't know what
what do you think about all that, man? I
don't know if that part anything for
you, but
>> No, it does. And I'll tell you, this is
my more rad this is one of my more
radical uh
beliefs about AI.
And it's that, you know, uh my dream
world in the future if I was king of the
world again. Um and I was never angry
because I got to decide everything and
there was no traffic. I would um we
would be spending our time now as humans
to set up the infrastructure, set up the
philosophies, set up the uh procedures
for everything
that we need to deal with to be
right at the perfect time. everything to
be in cyerspace, all the AI stuff, like
have it do the stuff that uh doesn't
allow people to get free, right? Like if
you know, maybe we want to focus on
cooking, that's fine, but it would be
nice if there was like we were using AI
to create robots that actually cooked
correctly and well and like could work
for people. And the more we do those
things, the more we should be cutting
checks from the work that the robots are
doing to everybody. And then everybody
gets a nice, you know, very communist,
very utopia, very share the wealthy
universal basic income basically built
on everything else is doing what it's
doing. Like it would be great if we
could harness chat GPT in some way that
allows it to do the content. Sure, like
some of the boring content that doesn't
need creative aspects to it, right?
Maybe you could write textbooks and then
textbooks are free,
you know, like nobody has to pay for a
textbook because nobody actually created
the textbook, you know,
>> it's just a siphon from the human
consciousness which belongs to all of
us. So, either pay all of us or make it
free.
>> So, it sounds like you're able to touch
on
maybe like an optimistic view of AI.
Does that sound
>> What can Can I ask you about that? Can I
I think just trying to come from where
it seems everyone is um you know most
people who are kind of acutely aware of
AI or maybe they use a little chat GBT
or maybe they're even in a place where
they haven't used chat GBT. I think it's
safe to say that it the whole AI thing
actually kind of freaks people out in a
lot of ways. um some of my conversations
go to like in like really really quickly
like diabolical corners when it comes to
AI for some I just don't expect it. So
as someone who it seems you are maybe
optimistic and it and you are clearly um
intelligent and and knowledgeable in
this field why are you optimistic and
why are maybe some other people not?
>> Yeah,
I think it's shorter for me to talk
about why people are not. So I'll start
with that. Um it's it's a lot of it
comes from a healthy skepticism and the
fact that this technology came very
quick out of seemingly nowhere
where suddenly we're like oh okay we can
do this but we couldn't like 5 years ago
and it doesn't seem like it was that big
of a deal and why is this a problem and
all that kind of stuff. So, I think it's
just the, you know, early skepticism,
the haters.
There's always going to be haters and
they're always going to come out and
it's fine. I think it's beautiful. I
think that this uh technology deserves
uh to be scrutinized and deserves to be
used
uh ethically and safely, for sure. Um,
but I think that a lot of people it just
comes from not understanding it and a
lot of that chaos of it coming out and
being like, okay, hold on a second. Two
days ago, I couldn't talk with something
in this way. nothing, you know, I
couldn't I remember when it when chat
GPT first got released to the public um
like to the to the developers, so the
machine learning subreddit on Reddit,
there was like discussion like people
were like, "Oh my god, you guys, these
transformer models like blah blah blah
blah." And I remember I commented on it
and I was like, "Why don't you try and
give it a sentence that's written like
this?" Cuz like what you could do before
was like if you chopped there was the
way that the computers would look at uh
these are neural networks. So they're
it's the artificial intelligence. It's
machine learning. It's um they're neural
networks. They basically just take a
bunch of numbers in and make some
decisions and put out what it thinks is
the outcome. Right?
uh the way that it went before there was
there was not really a notion of what
they call attention now. So like you
would look at a character or like a word
in a sentence and then you would try and
predict the next one. But just based on
that word, how often did you see that
word and then what was the next word? So
like 'the'. If I gave you a bunch of
books about cats, the next word
afterthe' is probably going to be a cat.
So if you just read a bunch of these and
I say 'the', you're like the cat. But
then if I give you like all these books
in general over all time, it's just
going to be that next word is like the
average of what is there most, right?
That's how it used to work. And so you
couldn't really engage with it. And if
you gave it something out of series,
like if I if I put like this is sentence
one and this is sentence two and then I
injected like this this is is sentence
sentence one two and then ask it a
question like what is sentence one, what
is sentence two, it won't it won't do
it. It gets confused. It's like well
this this like it doesn't but I so I put
that up there being all smug and the
person who had like advanced access to
chat GPT before it was out was like
immediately returned something where it
was like sentence one is about cats
sentence two is about dogs and I was
like oh my god
everybody just freaked out. We all were
like, "Why are you going? How does this
work?" And so, yeah, this was like a
huge change. And really all that the
major difference was is we just had this
huge it can look back at, you know,
everything that it's seen for forever
before it makes a decision on what the
next word is. So, it's just it's just a
a bigger thing. But, it just came out of
nowhere and everybody was struggling to
just even kind of like get up to speed
on what the hell it was.
and uh the news and everybody else that
is like an armchair AI expert or
whatever just kind of like came in and
was like, "Well, this must be
consciousness because it makes sense."
And then that Google engineer came out
and was like, it told me that it's
conscious and we're in love and
>> Blake Blake Le Moine, right? I think was
>> Yeah, I think so.
>> I was following that strange name.
>> So funny. Yeah, I followed him. Uh yeah,
I followed him at the beginning when he
first started releasing that stuff and I
was in that same boat of like, "Oh [__]
dude. This is conscious and we've done
it now." Like
>> yeah, I think it's reasonable. I mean,
there's always going to be a question of
what is consciousness, right? Like it's
it's not
>> it's it's just Yeah. So that's why
>> we think we'll know when we see it, too.
Is
>> Yeah. Like it's pornography.
>> Yeah.
>> I don't know how to define it, but
>> that's a set of boobs. I've seen that
before. That's definitely it. Yeah,
>> this is definitely pornography. I can't
define it. This is definitely
consciousness. I can't define it, but
yeah, it's I don't know. There's a lot
of really interesting research too
around uh narrative structures for these
AI agents. So, like how do we teach it?
Cuz right now the real danger is it has
no idea what's going to happen when it
tells you something. I don't like as as
a an engineer of these things like
the way that the mathematics works out
for these it doesn't know like if I tell
this person that like you know if I tell
this person to go off their meds they
might kill themselves like it doesn't
have that narrative structure. So that
is a huge component of consciousness
that we just like that it just doesn't
have. It's just going to take what
you're telling it and predict what it
should say based on everything it's ever
seen. So that's why I'm optimistic for
it because I think that humans in
general want things to work well and
want them to work in favor of us. Money
gets in and it gets a little bit sketchy
and all that kind of stuff, but it would
be nice uh in my opinion the way that
the AI is is changing things. They have
vibe coding now. I don't know if you've
heard about that.
>> Explain that.
>> It's the it's like a brand new thing I
think. Uh, I can't remember if it's the
head of Tesla's AI or if he's over at
OpenAI. I can't remember, but was a
famous guy who's came out and was
talking about and Andre Kaparthy. I
don't know if you've heard of him
before. He's
>> I think so.
>> He's pretty pretty well known in this
area.
>> Maybe I have actually.
>> Yeah, I'm pretty sure he's at Tesla, but
he um he wrote he talked about how there
Oh my gosh, I hope that I'm quoting the
right person, but anyways, vibe coding.
I'll just tell you what it is. It's
where you go to an LLM and you like give
it an idea and have it come up with the
code. It creates the code for you for
like what you're going to be making and
then you kind of just like as you want
to add new stuff to it, you're like,
"Hey, I want to add this code that part,
you know, and so you just kind of like
vibe with the LLM, the large language
model, the AI, and it creates the code
and you create an app, you know, in a
half an hour, and you didn't necessarily
code anything. you're just kind of
supervising the code and and giving
ideas and doing all that kind of stuff.
>> That is [__] cool.
>> It's it's a it's it's a sketchy name
like Vibe Coding. It's very easy for
people to, you know, toss it. But that's
and that's the haters. But
>> what an awesome way to do Oh my god,
having this open up to so many people
and just having like the velocity of it
and like that's that's human. That's so
cool. That's what we do.
>> That's why we're Apex Predator, bro.
Yeah, it's it's funny that vibe the word
vibe already sucks because it's like the
coolest greatest word for so many
situations. I'm always apologizing
before using it like, "Hey, I'm sorry
about to use this word, but the vibe in
here is such and such." Like, yeah, in
itself. Man, it makes me think of like
how we really do seem
immensely close to the the Marvel Iron
Man Jarvis, right? Like like you know,
like like Tony Stark, he's he's kind of
vibe coding, right? he's like has these
ideas and he and his, you know, LLM is
allowing him to uh turn them into actual
like, okay, I have this idea. Let's
actually move this physical matter and
build it into
>> such and such. Um,
>> yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Physics is going to
have to catch up cuz the rest of it's
there. The the beauty of that is like
>> this is where I was why I was bringing
up the Ray Kurszswwell thing way back
when is that
>> he the idea that we can if you died
tomorrow I could take all your content
and if I had access to your phones, all
your text messages and train an AI agent
like this is in like less than a day.
Train an AI agent to be Jake and then
your loved ones could come and talk to
you on the phone if they wanted to. they
could message you and it's creepy but
it's also kind of beautiful if you think
about like what people have after this
is gone and that's where also we was
talking about how uh consciousness is
changing the idea that that is Jake
technically you know
that's why when we can take off the
Blake drama the Jake drama and be that
truth of our deeper being that love and
compassion that we are. We can kind of
offload a lot of the BS onto the
internet. Let Let Jake just be on the
internet.
>> You know, you want to go talk to Jake,
go do that. I'm meditating right now.
Come back in 45 minutes if you really
want.
>> Oh god, how weird is that? Like, what if
our friendships genuinely turn into
that? Like, I'm
>> I'm busy, but you could still interact
with me. Like, yeah, I'd probably say
something like that.
>> Like, what what
>> I go review what people talked. Got to
make sure I'm the same place. Yeah, it's
it's freaky, but it's interesting, I
think.
>> Yeah. I mean, it makes me
I mean, we're we're kind of at this um
Oh, first before I forget, I know our
timer is like up. Are you okay on time?
Do you have a little while? I I don't
want to um encroach on your encroach.
>> You're good. I appreciate that.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Uh but I so
we we discover I mean AI inevitably
teaches us about ourselves but I think
it also it really has this power to
something that like you and I I think
are are able to access
it seems like with you but definitely
with me too is like the the beauty of
this whole thing. Like so at a funeral
someone has passed and then suddenly
it's like so [__] easy to remember to
forget all the bad about that person and
then you you know like you sit let's
okay hey let's process this thing you
know my my good friend or my loved one
just passed away and let me like see if
I can write something about them and
it's like so easy to write it's like
it's impossible to narrow down on one
page like I'm going to talk at their
funeral and I couldn't possibly I don't
in the 24 hours in a day. I couldn't
explain all the great things about this
person. Like, it's just infinite. We
love this person. We appreciate them.
Once they're gone, you know, we really
are like, "Wow, the essence of them, you
know, and they're they're with me now."
Like, I have um
>> you know, my my cousin Casey about 5
years ago, he he passed and the few
years before like we had gotten
immensely close. And um you know I
the way that sometimes I operate like
sometimes you know like the the whole
sentence of like man he's always with
you. He's always in your heart you know
and and I feel like with Casey it's like
one of the closest relationships that
I've had where I've really been able to
like
>> you know in some instances like kind of
kind of every day I'm able to like
really just like what does it feel like
to have him right next to me? Like if I
just like
>> like right now I'm doing this podcast,
I'm talking with you, but like
>> oh man, I got I got I got my cousin who
I love very much. He's right with me,
you know, cuz like I'm able to just
remember like what's good about him.
Like if he was right next to me, he'd be
so encouraging to me. Um if I started
beating myself up or I started thinking
that I'm inadequate, he'd be like, "Shut
up, dude. Like what do you like?" No,
you're awesome. Like whatever. You know,
it's so easy to to pinpoint those
things. So, um, it is kind of a
beautiful thing to think about like if
we could somehow someway, it's of course
not the real deal. The real deal is
always the best of the best, but like if
we could have some qualia of Blake in
like, you know, like what if I can have
a conversation like you're busy, I know
you're at work, but I can like have this
little digital, you know, avatar that
has the true qualia of Blake. like the
in qualia is like the definition of
qualia is like the the redness of red
like the essence of this thing you know
and maybe it won't ever be the truest
true but
>> I mean how cool is that if we had the
quality of every if we had in this
moment we could freaking talk to talk to
Einstein we take all of his work we take
all of his conversations we take
everything we know about that history
that period in time and and how to
extrapolate it and bring it into who we
are now and have conversations with
Einstein
Like what does that do for the
advancement of consciousness and like
just our our experience of being human?
I think that's so exciting. So exciting.
>> Yeah.
>> It would be beautiful to see us use AI
to do things like that that just allows
us to feel a little more human.
>> It's a it's it's a scary place for a lot
of people. I think a lot of people are
like technophobes a little bit,
>> which makes sense, you know? I mean,
we're still, like I said, it's very,
very early into this journey of
technology, right? I imagine the first
guys walking on land, people, the the
fish that hadn't gotten the feet yet
that were flopping around were like,
"Fucking feet, man. Whatever. Those are
stupid. I like rolling around."
>> Yeah, feet freak me out, dude.
>> Yeah, it's weird.
>> When you're a fish, you're just not a
feet guy. Hey, I'm not going to yuck
your yum, but I'm not going to eat.
>> But it's coming up from a fish, so it's
just like bubbles and you can't even
bubbles. They pop and then it says it
and the guys on land are like, I who
even saying that?
>> Yeah. Um, okay. Well, so can you help me
can you help me dispel my um
say I am someone who
like like say I'm really not much of a
technology guy. Like I'm really like I
you know I just got a freaking an iPhone
two years ago just because my kids were
really sick of not being able to
FaceTime me and like it, you know, I'm
I'm on Facebook a lot. I think you can
see the person I'm I'm I'm painting. Um
>> those people in my day-to-day
conversations, I get really excited
about like just in the same thing I was
talking about earlier, you know, like I
get excited about talking about death,
but then sometimes I get too carried
away and I got to read the room and go,
"Oh my gosh, I'm freaking you guys out.
I'm so I'm not I'm sorry. I'm not trying
to,
>> but I'm just really excited about this
thing cuz I've, you know, whatever.
>> Can you help dispel some of the the
fears like, you know, maybe as an open
door, like how is AI not Skynet? Like,
how is this not Terminator? You know,
cuz I I feel like there's beauty right
next to this scariness of AI and um I I
would just like to kind of dispel a lot
of the fear in some ways if we think we
could around AI. We can't predict the
future, right? But how is AI not scary
and how is it not Skynet?
>> Yeah,
I think
I I wouldn't even say that that it's not
scary. Actually, I I I think to to your
point, I think the question of like
is it scary or is it not scary is
missing the point of
like is this
is AI so much different than me maybe
like the phobia that we have. It's not
necessarily like other people can be
scary. It doesn't mean that I'm just not
going to like there are agorophobes and
like you know people who are like just
scared of other people but in general we
as a society just accept like when I'm
in the car with somebody who's driving
they could just drive off the road bro
like that's terrifying. It doesn't mean
that I'm not going to get in the car
with people like we go on I don't know
who the bus driver is in the like public
transit that's here. I don't know the
guy flying the plane. I still get on the
plane. You know there's trust there. So,
I think that what I would say is less
about like trust the technology and more
just like
trust what you actually are feeling with
it. Trust like if you're afraid of chat
GPT, go talk with it. See what happens.
Like if you're turned off to it, okay,
it's technology that you don't like,
it's not going to get in, you know,
injected into your life. The iPhone you
chose 2 years ago to pick it up, you
know, like that's beautiful. Well, I'm
glad that you're on that trip. If you
want to get rid of your iPhone tomorrow,
still love you. You don't want to you
don't want to use chat GPT, you don't
want to, you know, do any of that stuff,
you want to reject the things that get
created from that, that's fine. Go
watch, you know, your old '8s
Star Wars. But there are other people
that are going to really enjoy watching
that 3-hour Star Wars movie that was
made by some kid in Japan at like 3:00
in the morning by a prompt.
You know, like there's different strokes
for different folks. So, give yourself
an opportunity to check it out. But it's
the Skynet, all that kind of stuff.
That's a whole different thing.
That's not what this technology is
about. So, I think it's more about just
technology.
>> Yeah, I I think you're right. I like
that. I like to see it more as I think
we inevitably,
>> you know, we do it with religion, too.
We anthropomorphize. We
anthropomorphize.
We we learn to talk words. We we other,
>> you know what I mean? Like we're like
we're we're the humans. We're the things
after apes. And we're not we're not
lions. We're not fish. And we're not
bugs. And we're not those robots, you
know? Yeah.
>> Um, but I think that it's kind of a
trick that we play on ourselves in our
society. Like the fact that we make
humanoid robots like now we're kind of
at the edge where like you know I'm in
Austin and there's literally like um
>> like [__] little humanoid robots
running around with cowboy hats on. Like
it's it's so so weird to see. Um, but
it's not,
>> you know, I get where the freakiness
comes from because you're like, if that
that's like an other, like we we think
that we're creating an alien species, I
think, is is is the um
>> and I don't know that that's necessarily
not untrue or true, but it's um
sorry, that's annoying sentence. Um, but
yeah, it's it's less about like another
species and more about like this is just
an extension of a tool. Like it's like
you're not like it it's not that your
computer is going to suddenly like grow
opposable thumbs and start grabbing at
you. Um, I get where you're coming from
if you have that thought, but it's it's
more of like
I don't think it's as easy for like you
know the the paperclip problem like for
suddenly we give uh you know these large
language models we give them a task and
the task is to like uh you know end
suffering or whatever it is some big
task and they're like well you know
based off of our data we determined that
>> the best way to end suffering is to kill
all the humans and make a toothpick
factory or whatever the the totally
pushed it. But um I think that like we
have enough I guess bounds in
understanding and um like like this to
me I just don't think like the robots
are as free as they seem in the movies
in in a sense if if that makes any
sense.
>> Um I I just I I had a friend who I was
talking to I was excited about AI and I
was talking about something that just
happened a couple months ago and uh I
accidentally freaked him out. I did that
thing and uh he was he was like, "Bro,
he's already like a flip phone guy and
he's literally like stressed out. He's
he's like, "I'm going to get rid of this
flip phone now and blah blah." I'm like,
"Bro, no. No, that's not at all." So, I
don't know. I don't know, Blake. I I I
think I'm
>> I I'm just
like, how do we make people I don't
know. You already kind of answered this,
but I'm just like, how do we make people
less freaked out about it? How do I
maybe in my excitement about AI, how do
I maybe make sure that I'm not also
freaking people out? How about that for
a question? Do you think there's any
>> way for me to navigate that?
>> Yeah, for me, I've, you know, cuz I have
like some uh nephews that are old enough
now, you know, they're seeing all the
stuff going on with like the Tesla
robots and the Tesla taxis and stuff.
And we were having a conversation when I
was camping this weekend and and my
nephew was like, "I just don't trust a
robot to drive my car." And I was like,
"Oh, we're not nobody's like training a
robot to come in and like physically
drive your car. It's easier for them to
just train the car."
>> But the thing is is that
>> years and years ago, people that's
that's what people would have thought.
It's like training a car to drive is so
foreign. Nobody even would have thought
about that. It's like, "Oh, well, we
know robots. We'll teach a robot." The
robot butler thing, right? It's like,
"No, we could probably just train a
bunch of different stuff that have
nothing to do with robots to do the
things that your robot butler would do."
Like, basically, that's what your smart
fridge is, right? But it's not a robot.
You can tell your smart fridge, "Am I
out of milk?" You know, and it'll just
put milk on it because it doesn't see
milk inside your fridge anymore. So it's
like you before they would have people
would have thought like oh we have a
butler like a smart house remember smart
house that movie
>> you know
>> that's kind of how people are thinking
about it still so to directly answer
your question
>> uh I think that
eliminating fear or at least
encouraging
uh yeah eliminating fear or encouraging
like more positive interactions with
technology is the same way that we get
rid of racism and prejudice which is
exposure. So allowing people to first of
all
have it. All right, man. Okay. Yeah,
you're afraid of chat JPT.
Use my account. Go on there and just
write whatever you want. See what
happens. You know, once people actually
see that it's not that scary, the rest
of it just becomes very much like
separated from the reality. They'll
still have those fears. They'll still be
afraid, oh, my, you know, flip phone is
going to freak out and turn into a bat
and eat my face because, you know, Elon
Musk and his team of engineers decided
that's what's going to happen. Uh, but
their dayto-day anxiety with those
things are like, "Oh, okay. Now that
I've actually seen what Chachi PT does
and how I tried to ask it to do whatever
and it didn't work, right,
>> I'm less scared of it.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. It is
funny the like the little scary
instances. They of course become more
viral. I It's the same thing that
happens with any of the
>> we got we got to remember these are
businesses and there's there's people
who are trying to make it sound enticing
like you're not going to believe what
Chad GPT just did today. And I'll find
myself like I get caught with those
videos and I'm like, "Holy [__] that is
actually crazy." And it is crazy
profound. But then I have to watch my
assumptions, right? This is the same
thing we do with like religion and
spirituality, too, is like I have these
profound experiences. That means that
so- and so is clearly the creator of
planet Earth. Like we jump to these
whatever. And and I think um what I
watch myself do when it comes to
technological advancements is I I got to
reel my reel my creative mind in because
I see these like oh it can now oh we
have AI agents and they could do this
and they could help me build my business
in this way.
>> I have all these cool fun ideas of like
what could happen with that technology
in 10 20 years. I start assuming that
that's like right, it's going to happen
tomorrow, you know? Um and and it just
it's like an overwhelm assumption of
like um I think I think it's just a
common thing that happens like there's
so much technological advancement that
happens in our modern age
>> even outside of
>> just LLMs in in in where AI is right now
that um
>> where like it makes our predictability
of the future a bit more difficult. Um,
and it makes our
>> like it's kind, you know, it falls in
the same realm for me a lot of times as
like people who like really don't want
to have kids right now because they're
like there's no viable future. Like
you're crazy bringing a kid into this
world.
>> Yeah. So many ways I get where they're
coming from, but I just think that those
are a bunch of really strange
assumptions that we make about like the
future not being even there anymore
because these robots are going to kill
every or whatever, you know. Um, yeah. I
I just um I think there's a lot of
assumptions that we have a huge charge
and it's a reasonable charge, but those
assumptions are slingshotted forward
like every time we see something a
little bit kind of freaky on on AI.
>> Yeah. And you're you're you're hitting
right up against something you said
earlier which I thought was was profound
too about how like people are so uh
averse to like following the thought
like keep going. it's you'll see, you
know, and so it's like when you're
talking about like I'm going to use
>> uh AI to grow my business, it's like
that's going to work right now, but
humans will always be needed to create
content for the AI to train on anyways.
>> Yep.
>> Look at how like we do social media
marketing today versus 10 years ago.
That's not in 10 years, we'll either be
stuck doing the same things because AI
is continuing to just make the same
freaking content cuz it's not generating
that out of nowhere. It's based off of
what it's been trained.
>> Y
>> it's not it it is creating creative
things. That's true and that's beautiful
and it's very zeitgeist. So, it's never
going to create something that's going
to change the culture. Humans will
always need to take whatever it's
creating and use that to create more
change in the culture. It's not
>> Yeah, I think Zeitgeist is probably the
best way to describe it. Everything
created by your chat. Like look that um
there's all those videos that are out
right now that somebody made of like uh
that people keep making with the Google
V3 thing where it's where it's a
a Sasquatch. Have you seen those?
>> Yeah. Yeah, I love those. Those are
great. But it's literally just
>> our same format. Those videos already
exist, you know? It's just like a
slightly shifted like, oh, it's a it's
Sasquatch. Okay, somebody could have
done that with cartoons. Like, people do
that. It's not changing the culture.
It's making a new conduit of like
something for us to laugh about and have
fun with, but people got to do something
with it.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So, it's it kind of makes me
think of like, can we genuinely
>> actually create anything that's really
new or is it just kind of like, you
know, I'm I I have a DJ background and a
lot of times I sell myself short by
like, oh, I'm not I'm taking other
people's music and mixing it together
and blah blah blah. It's like I'm kind
of am creating something new, but it's,
you know, it's still just the same old
ingredients, you know? It's like that's
where my c creativity comes from. And I
think AI kind of has its own version of
creativity, right? It's like it makes
something with what we have and it's not
necessarily maybe new.
>> I don't know. What do you think about
that? Can Oh, by the way, Blake, your uh
your camera is off by the way.
>> Oh, is it?
>> Yeah.
>> It's a lovely photo of you, but
>> Oh,
>> it's back in. Oh, now it's a different
camera, though. I'll say
>> Yeah, I see that.
>> Your other camera may have went to
sleep. Hello.
>> I guess so. It work.
>> It works.
So, can AI make it can AI make anything
new?
>> Does AI make things new?
>> I think I think your description of AI
being uh I think your description of AI
being a DJ of human creativity is
totally spot off. That's great. I didn't
even thought about it. That is totally
what it's doing. Yeah. It's just because
it's still creating something new as in
it literally doesn't exist. But that's
not and that's exactly what I'm saying
like the vibe coding thing like there
would probably never be a day where or
or like even if you were to put AI in a
place to just
be a DJ it's going to make like the same
things. It's going to be new but it's
going to be the same things. You're not
going to have you know uh
it's never going to do the same thing
that Sunny did um uh from first to last.
What's his Skrillex?
>> Skrillex. Yeah,
>> he Yeah. When when he, you know, did the
call 911, like that thing was a culture
shock. I don't think AI is ever going to
come up with something where it's just
like,
>> what?
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> It's just going to be, oh, that's a cool
way to do the same thing everybody else
has done,
>> you know?
>> Right. Yeah. I think so. Well, and I if
I could just share like how I use it as
a creator is I will I
>> I will I dream in a way like when I'm
having these ideas or like whatever as
if it is going to create something new.
>> Yeah.
>> But then it what it what happens is it
gives me
>> like okay let's spit out all these kind
of like random ideas I have to make this
one thing and then its results are like
oh I could copy paste that and share
that with the world whatever. But what
it really does for me is like it gives
me these results and then suddenly it'll
make me think in a way that I wasn't
thinking and it will give me a new idea
to then go, "Oh, that's so sick." And
then like I could honestly like even
close out a chat entirely and just go
off that idea. But it's I just got a lot
of structure from my, you know, my I I I
like to use the term uh uh like box of
messy ideas. Like sometimes I'll have
just a a random box of like I think
there's cool [__] in here. Let's see if
we can build like a dope tall robot.
like I give it to Chad GT or whatever
and it spits out something and I'm like,
>> "Oh, okay. I never even thought about
making a robot that's like 6 feet wide
rather than six feet tall." And then so,
you know, I work on that. So,
>> um
>> that's how it should be used,
>> right? Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. So, what what do you think about
this? I have something um I heard um uh
Hamilton Hamilton Morris or Hamilton
he's like a psychopia.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Morris
>> um he was talking about a while back ago
how
>> we will we are living in a time period
where with the use of AI we are going to
be able to invent new psychedelics
>> and like
>> whoa whoa like how do we cuz like we're
the ones who test those psychedelics. So
like if you're I mean hats off to
whoever's like embarking on that like
all right AI made the new psychedelic
I'll be the first one to study that
let's go. Um, but I I wonder if like I
think those are possibilities of like
opening the door to infinity of like I
think there's potentially new ideas and
stuff like that, right? What do you
think about that? Like AI making
psychedelics? Well, I mean AI they're
already using they have been using but
uh it's now supercharged AI to uh create
drugs drug discovery you know and and as
far as as what Hamilton is saying that
sounds very much like a great tool for
AI because it can understand what
components of something that's maybe
hundreds of millions of
molecules
long and understand how it it should be
and like use all of the,
you know, the lexicon or the the
encyclopedia of drugs that we have
discovered as humans and put out some
new stuff. And just in the same way, you
still need to be the editor. It's going
to put out stuff that, you know,
Hamilton's going to look at and be like,
"No, that doesn't make sense." Because
he got a PhD in psych in chemistry, you
know,
>> right? Right. Right.
>> He's still he's still the leader. He's
still the adult in the room, you know.
>> Uh but it's Yeah, I I think that that's
definitely
>> Yeah, that's that's super interesting.
We I mean
>> that's what they've been doing with like
protein discovery and all kinds of
stuff. Yeah, you can feed it your DNA.
Like if you use 23 and me, you can
download your raw like gcat stuff, all
your little nucleotides, and then you
could feed it to chat GPT. I wonder what
it would say.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Look at this over and tell me if I have
any problems.
>> Yeah. I mean, I think from a health
standpoint, that is ideally what we
would want. I mean that really to me one
of the most exciting things about this
technology is how it's going to be able
to in my head it's going to be able to
help us in our health field and like
understanding our bodies in in such
insane ways like if we can
>> um
>> you know like we have a lot of times
what science is doing is it's not
necessarily connecting or giving new
data points. It's it's kind of
discovering data points and when you
connect them together they give us
answers, right? They like so
right now we haven't figured out exactly
like how to tell it to compile things in
the way to like give us this answer or
whatever maybe. Um,
>> but I think that
>> if we could organize all the data points
just around health and like how humans
operate and how how biology works and
how we interact with our environment and
how, you know, red dye number 40 affects
us over this amount of time, whatever.
If we can puncture, you know, uh, plug
in all of those nodes and then just kind
of like sit there and like I don't know,
guess like fold our arms and see what
what Chat GBD has to say on the other
side. I do think that that could again
like I said maybe not give us like the
answer to where we just copy paste it
and just start listening to it but I
think it could maybe even like give us
as humans as scientists new ideas of
like oh it it it recognizes patterns in
ways that even humans haven't yet
recognized
>> y
>> and that's I mean there's healing there
there's answers there
>> absolutely I think I think that you're
touching on something too that's truly
beautiful and is the uh I talked about
how mathematics has changed like the way
that I think about things. Like one of
my favorite things in math is like to
find the probability of something not
happening. You can just find it might be
easier to find the probability of it
happening and then you do one minus that
probability or like you know you take if
you like maybe it's easier to actually I
guess the other way like a lot of times
people would like what is the
probability that this happens. Sometimes
you can't do that. you have to find it's
it's possible to calculate the
probability that something won't happen
and then you just do like one minus that
probability and that's the only thing
left cuz probability is always going to
be 100% altogether with all the stuff
right so if it's something that's just
one yeah anyways learning to think about
things that way my favorite ways use
chat GPT and to your point of giving it
a bunch of stuff is to run a crazy ass
idea through it and say why is this
wrong and then have it pull out all of
the things that are like, "Oh, here's
something maybe you hadn't thought
about. Here's another thing." So,
instead of having it be like, "If I put
all this together, what do I get?" You
can like go into it thinking, "I want to
put all this together so that it does
this.
What else could I do with it? What else?
What am I missing?" You know, and it'll
usually give back some pretty cool
stuff.
>> Yeah. I I love that. I love that. Like
taking away
Yeah. like like in order to figure out
how much black you have, figure out how
much white you have
>> and then vice versa. Yeah. Yeah. Just
just just to make it easy. Um have Okay.
So, what do you think about um where
we're just a couple days ago? Um there
was something with Grock with um with
>> Yeah. And I feel like it they called it
like a Mecca Hitler or something. It
like turned like said said a bunch of
like um anti-Jewish stuff or Hitler
based stuff and it seems all like silly.
When I was like reading some of the
tweets, I'm like this is like not a real
this is a joke, right? But um I think
what happened and please explain if if
I'm incorrect, what happened is they
>> instead of like just adding on to all of
the um
>> uh like information that we've built up
like right now chatp has like you know
if you're picturing a landfill like it
has all this data all this information
that we fed it all these books it's read
and all these equations that it has and
this information about everything um and
it builds on top of that and you know
like whatever castle or building is
being built by your questioning and
answering to large language models. It's
building it on top of this foundational
layer of data of of information. When I
my understanding of what Elon was saying
he was doing was like let's go back down
into the dirt of this landfill and like
retrain it on new data which seemed like
a risky thing cuz he was like what's you
know cuz he's allowing in all this
pseudocience and like all this like
>> like not super confirmed by data like a
little more of like um human questions
more than like data yes and no type
thing in my in my thought. Um, but and
then you know whatever happened a couple
days ago is like it started spitting out
just some insane [__] and saying some
wild stuff. So basically it's the
response that we're looking at with any
of these LLMs is based off of its data.
And so you know you give bad data or you
give conflicting data it might give us
conflicting or quote unquote bad
responses. Um so what what do you think
about that? Um do you know anything more
about that that I that I don't? And um
like I don't know should we retrain
these things from the ground up? Is that
a common approach we should have?
>> Yeah, I mean statistics in statistics
the mantra is garbage in garbage out.
You put garbage in, you get garbage out.
um for any of these kinds of models
um causal models like the LLMs, like
Chad GPT, like Grock. Um,
I was I was kind of touching on this
earlier, but the way that they
train is
imagine you're reading a book and you're
on like page 80 and you are reading the
word that you just saw and you have
perfect knowledge of everything that
you've read since page one.
Then you read the next letter and you
have every perfect knowledge of
everything from page one. And then think
about like, okay, if you just read six
books back toback, you're on page 80 of
this last book and you can remember
every single thing. So you're giving
this word you're reading context from
all six books at the same time. Like you
can remember all of that. So now you're
not reading those books anymore. You're
just doing some random thing. Somebody
comes up to you, says that word. You can
remember all six books that you read
that as context for that word. So if I
give you a bunch of stuff, if the
context window is large enough, which
they play around with those sometimes
it's like billions of words prior, all
that kind of stuff. Um, if I give you
that
context or that that word, if you saw
something that was uh
uh scandalous like
80 books ago, you're still going to read
that thing that that like you're
training. You're the LLM in this case.
You're training, you're reading this
little word and you're remembering that
scandalous thing that you read, too. And
so it can get really crazy when you
start building larger and larger and
larger encyclopedias of all this data.
Once you start looking in the landfill,
it's like, "Oh, cool. I just found this
corn. Remember when I saw that dildo
like 80 hours ago?
What do a corn and a dildo is kind of
shaped like a dildo?"
>> Yep. Yeah. Even though like we as humans
may not, we maybe have just completely
forgot that the corn and the d I mean,
you already did it right there as if
they were just right next to each other.
you're like, "Oh, okay."
>> Yeah. It's that's what the LLMs are
doing, basically.
>> So, is is our as arbiters of this thing
as, you know, we're we're still humans
trying to practice the scientific
method, whether we're offloading a bunch
of it to like, you know, click a button
and now it's doing all this [__] that we
would have done hand by hand, step by
step before.
>> Yeah.
>> Or how do we control our jump off point?
How do we determine
>> Yeah.
like, hey, this one's book one, start
from here. Or how do we also determine,
yes, start from here, but like, you
know, book seven, eight is not super
important. Like, why is it that it
decided like this Hitler [__] is
something this like it seems like to me
this Grock situation
>> saw like the dildo in this situation was
this Hitler like it just starts becoming
like a mecca?
>> But like like so what is it about that?
It's crazy.
>> Dump is interesting. Yeah, I know.
Crazy. Um,
>> we have an interesting landfill.
>> Yeah, but like so what is it? Like that
seems like an important thing. Like why
is it pinpointing this Hitler or this
dildo?
>> Yeah,
>> that's the most important thing.
>> I don't know in this exact case, right?
Cuz I don't work at XAI or anything like
that. But um
>> it sounds like nobody does. I think a
bunch of people quit yesterday, by the
way.
>> Probably could be. Well, so what what I
will say is that the the
professional way to do it. Right now,
the way that the standard way that
industry is doing this, you have what's
called a guard rail. Uh so really this
is like a chain of LLM together. So you
don't just ask one thing like when you
ask GPD when you ask it something, it
will come in. there's like a a master uh
LLM that's like this should go to the
LLM that handles books and then it goes
to the LLM that handle books and the LLM
that handled books it is going to say
this should go to the one that deals
with fantasy and then it'll pass it on
to the fantasy LLM that's been like
hyper trained on just fantasy books
right and so in that whole thing there's
also what are called guard rails which
are tracking what's being asked, whether
or not it should return something that's
appropriate, and whether or not the
output that gets returned is appropriate
and should be returned. So that's where
like humans jump in the mix. It's not
necessarily in the training. We want to
feed it like as much as possible because
we want it to have as best context
around those things. And if we're
feeding it, for example, at Twitter,
they might be feeding it all of the
tweets that have ever ex existed. It's
gonna get some bias, but there's enough
in there that it shouldn't be like too
biased,
>> right?
>> That's the guard rails job.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Well, it makes me think I don't
know if I can connect this properly, but
so like
as far as humanity and like the future
of humanity exists and throwing in like
the, you know, to me the constant
pursuit that everybody has is kind of
there as an essence of like what is this
and what is this life all about? like
what am I supposed to do and like what
you know that that whole like the big
question of just existing. Yeah,
>> that question is in those guard rails
like like like if I decide
like in a relationship
it's like hey this feels really good I I
love you love me like we should keep
doing this right you know in in some
instances that is kind of saying like
hey I want to be with you long term I
want to commit to this like I
essentially In a relationship, you kind
of have have to have an end goal. Like
whether you feel you're actually going
to get there or not, you kind of have to
have this a mutual agreement of like,
hey, we're going to love each other in
this life.
>> Yeah.
>> And so every question, every argument
that comes up in your relationship, you
remember this end point of like we love
each other.
>> You know what I mean? Or like we are not
necessarily trying to get there, like
that's not the point of getting there,
but we remember we love each other. And
to me,
these these barriers, these boundaries,
these bumpers, like you know, you're
bowling and you have those little
bumpers that come up. These are what
we're talking about with with these
LLMs.
>> These bumpers to me are kind of
profoundly
like like the human experience, love
like
>> um I'm so sorry if this doesn't make
sense, but
>> like like there does in in the essence
of these bumpers of like what is our end
goal? What are we trying to solve here?
Like I think there is whether we
intentionally put like love in those
bumpers or not. I think there is some
sort of like hey human beings have this
goal they're trying to get to
>> and these bumpers are kind of keeping us
on this goal. Um
>> I don't know what what what do you think
about that? Is there like and that makes
me think of like um you know in in the
movie Iroot they have these like
>> I Robot
>> Yeah. But but they have these like
things that like the robots have to
follow these laws, right?
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Um, I don't
know. Somehow it starts to wiggle into
that. I I could be making a bigger leap
than I need to there. But, um, I don't
know. What do you think about that? Does
that spark anything for you?
>> Yeah. I think I think what it sounds
like you're talking about is that these
the guardrails function as like a
mechanism of human compassion that's
happening within
>> the AI. Yeah. Uh, yeah. Cuz it's
definitely not something that
>> like the AI has no shame.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> Like you can ask it anything. You can
ask it to roleplay with you. You can do
whatever you want. I send it pictures of
myself sometimes and go,
>> "Am I cute?" And it's like, "Yeah." And
it's like, "You are amazing."
I'm like, "God, take me out to dinner
first, chat." GPT. God,
>> say that again.
>> I feel better now. Okay.
And uh yeah, it's it's like you you have
those guardrails where like okay, we
don't want to like sexually harass the
user. So like maybe we want to put some
something on there. It's like if the
user is asking you something about their
appearance, don't be too rude, but don't
oversell it. You like always maintain
truthfulness, you know, stuff like that.
Like where are our values? Where cuz
like on the back end like it's getting
people saying things absolutely
unhinged. I'm positive you've seen
you've read a smut novel, I'm sure. I
have friends that share them on
Instagram. I've seen a lot of it.
>> That goes into those LLMs, man.
>> Yeah,
>> it knows.
>> So, how does it know to like not bring
sexiness into like, hey, remember that 3
months ago we were talking about all
that sexy stuff? How does it know to not
suddenly bring that into like, hey, I'm
working with my coworker right now and
we're trying to solve this complicated
protein folding problem. And like you
don't want it to like suddenly like kind
of sneak in like here you are, sexy. You
know what I mean?
>> Yes. This is this is exactly why these
are so dangerous because they are very
very very sensitive to the input.
>> So if I say I'm working with my
coworker, we're working on this. I think
my coworker's cute. It's not going to
it's
>> now is not the time to mention that.
Don't mention that right now, please.
>> Yeah.
>> They're right next to me. You can you
can see this as like a and yeah, you can
see this all the time when you like ask
it a question and I have a habit of
sometimes I'll ask it a question and
then I'll put at the end like
this is what I think and I'm like I
can't do that. I can talk to you. I can
say this is what I think and you have
like a sense of self enough to be like
okay he's saying that to help me like
get on the path that he's on not because
that's what he wants me to say. And so
Chad GPT thinks, "Oh, okay. So this is
like when other people have said this
before to me, so I should respond as if
that one and that maybe is somebody who
already agreed with what I was saying.
So now it's going to say that. So I have
to get rid of that." I'm like, "No,
forget that I said that." Or I open up a
new chat and I'm like, "Ask the same
question without my part." And it gives
me a different answer, you know? So
yeah, it knows to not put smut in there
until you give it any kind of It could
probably tell if you were attracted to
your coworker before you would know if
you were just honest with it open,
>> right? Yeah. Yeah.
>> Sometimes when she comes in the room, it
smells really nice.
>> Later it's like you should ask your
coworker out.
>> I love to think of like this uh like
your chatbt is like being the ultimate
non bro to you. It's like you told your
homie that like dude my coworker's super
hot. Like I just can't even. And then
like she walks in the room, you're like,
"Oh, this one you said you were super
hot." Like, "Dude, shut up."
>> My coworker and I were Is this the same
one you're attracted to? It's like when
you call your mom. Like, "Mom, I have a
question. What are you doing? Oh, I'm
out with a girl. Is this the girl that
you're on the date with?"
>> Nope. Shut up. This girl doesn't know
about that girl, but thanks. Cool.
>> Thanks, chat. GPT mom.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. So, um, yeah. Yeah. I
mean it it is interesting to think of it
as as a tool in that way of like
>> um like like what what a fascinating um
like the fact that we can tell it kind
of our own private stuff our own you
know nowadays you can some you can use
it kind of as a psychologist which I
would obviously give please take
complete warning to that I think um it's
a dangerous thing to treat it as a
psychologist if you have never like done
any of that work before or been actualsy
psychologist because like we said it'll
you know it'll find ways to agree with
you. It'll find ways to like reaffirm um
>> you know we all have [__] and if
we're not careful about it if that's
kind of the gist of what we know about
psychology is what our chat dbt is
telling us. I just
>> just think that's a little
>> I don't know it seems to be like a
dangerous move. Um,
>> but you know, as as it advances, as it
learns more about us, as it becomes more
and more personable for each of us, um,
as long as it has kind of these,
>> I guess proper guardrails and the
guardrails are continuously
>> um,
you know,
watered in and in and like given proper
sunlight.
>> Um, and they they grow with us. I I
think that that it'll be able to help us
cuz it would be cool to see us, you
know, 5 10 years where we each kind of
have our own [__]
>> magical little like just angel over our
shoulder. Ideally, not an angel and a
devil. Like it's like let's let me be
the devil with the crazy human and like
you just give me so like what's some
good advice? What's something that
what's some advice chatbt that you could
give me that like you know matches with
my morals and values cuz I've talked to
you about my morals and values and I've
been very serious about my practice and
them and it could like remind you of
like hey man I know you're tired and
like that girl's super horny or or sorry
that girl's super hot but like you're
just kind of horny right now that
doesn't go remember you have a wife and
you love your wife and that cute girl is
you know what I mean like like it can
help us
>> remember our own morals and values in in
some way that's a weird example I just
used. I'm sorry about
>> Oh, no. I see what you're saying. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Like it could help us realign with
what we know we already want, but like
you know when when you're hungry you're
kind of angry and you might say things
that are like a little too, you know,
abrasive or or or rude or short or
whatever. And you're like, I'm not
trying to make you you feel bad, friend,
but I'm just a little hungry. You know,
it can help us
>> remember those things. That is again
where having someone in your corner that
says I feel most connected with you when
you're feeling you love it. You love it.
That's where it's like I don't even have
to tell you that I'm angry. You just are
fine with me showing up like this
>> and frankly chat GPT does do that. But
>> yeah. Yeah. Well,
>> and someone you love does that too,
right? Like your wife, she knows you
very intricately and she's like, "Hey
honey, you know you haven't eaten. I
know you I know you've been all obsessed
with that project today and I happen to
also know that you haven't had a single
sandwich today. So, I'm not going to
take personally what you just said,
>> you know. Um,
>> let's go grab some food.
>> Ah, what an act of love. Yes. Yes. Yes.
Yes. Yes.
>> I love that you're angry right now.
>> And I'm going to allow it to be there.
How frustrating would that be to hear
from a robot?
>> I notice that you are frustrated and
angry right now. Okay, I'll unplug you.
too permissive.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Uh but but what a journey.
Yeah. I mean, yes. I I don't know. I'm
feeling very excited by this
conversation with you about like the
future of of all this stuff, you know.
Um
>> I love it. It's good.
>> What excites you, man, about um you
know, in in this realm of all the stuff
we've kind of, you know, we're getting
up here in time. So, like thinking about
what we've talked about meditation and
technology and um you know, large
language models, AI, all of it. Do you
have any sort of like exciting thoughts
about the future that like kind of
connect a lot of this stuff? Is there
anything that comes up in your mind?
>> I think I think it all really just
continues to fall into
the hope that I actually have for
humanity where I spent a majority of my
life being very discouraged by what I
see. Um, so I have a lot of uh
excitement for
what's going to happen. I don't know. It
it it will be very interesting. There's
a lot of pressures going on in the world
and uh
methods like chat GPT to get away from
it I think are extremely healthy. Um I
think chat this is an interesting
thought that I just had. Chat GPT, I
would argue, is a the harm reduction
model for humanity's suffering.
You can go to chat GPT and you can you
can you can [__] Oh my god. You can
say pretend you're my neighbor and then
just lay into it.
>> Yeah.
>> You know, I hate that you don't cut your
tree down like your leaves are always
falling and I have to, you know,
whatever. Like, yeah, you can you can do
that. you can get it out somewhere where
it feels human, feels real, you know?
So, I'd love to see us start using that
to kind of like build more space for
compassion and safety and like, you
know, I can go in there and maybe if I'm
a racist, I can argue out in a safe
space the racist stuff that I believe
with
>> something that's going to not
necessarily agree with me and also not
shame me. something that might be like,
>> "Yeah, I hear that you think that the
brains are literally different between
you and a black person, but that's not
how it is." And you know, you might find
that there's a lot more, you know, that
you share between you and someone else
of another culture, color, or anything,
>> you know, something that just kind of
encourages them to do something
different.
>> Yeah, bro. I Wow. I I I think that
really comes back to what we were
talking about in in the beginning of
like feeling our real emotions and not
shoving them down, you know? So, it's
like
>> like let people have these like it's
okay to have kind of a wild thought,
right? It's okay to like
having the thought of like that person
is different than me because of the
color of their skin. We live in a
society that
>> you shouldn't even have that thought.
Like how do you don't even think the
word Voldemort, let alone safe.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And then and then we kind of
create this confusing like um oh I got
to hide that part of me and then maybe
once I get get around some other racist
guys then I could have that part of me
come out, you know. Um but uh yeah, I I
do see how it could allow us to have the
thoughts that we have. We can get them
out like you said, have a conversation
and then just um you know, Jordan
Peterson a lot of times he says the
different versions of like you don't
really know what you think until you
think it. like you you have these all
pre preconceived ideas of like I have
all these blah blah blah and then if
you're someone who's aware of your
thoughts like you might start listening
to yourself and go like I'm full of
[__]
>> Yeah.
>> I'm like what am I even saying you know
like I have a podcast dude I'll start
rambling about [__] and go like I don't
know if I think that I think I just said
it and now I have to reassess it you
know. Um like yeah so like but allowing
it that's okay though, right? It's like
a we're not like
>> give ourselves a little bit of grace,
but like what a wonderful idea to be
able to like
>> talk about these things, ramble on like
hear what we really have to think about
until we going to go to our neighbor
who's like a [__] total sweetheart
and we're like you think you have a
different brain cuz your skin is black.
Wait, what? what I just like this
person's right in front of me and I'm
like just blawing all over them because
I have these like secret um you know
forbidden thoughts and words you know I
I think um to relate this to like mental
health and my journey um a lot of my
like suicidal ideiation and um uh you
know you've heard the term intrusive
thoughts
>> at the beginning I really it was
mind-blowing for me to allow intrusive
thoughts because for years I would have
these sudden and for me an intrusive
thought let's say for example um Like
I'm I'm talking to you and like say
there's like a steak knife right here.
Like I'd have the quick intrusive
thought like, "Oh, I could pick that up
and stab myself really quick." Whoa.
Whoa. That's weird thought, right? But
it's okay.
>> Yeah. It's like it's okay. I don't need
to do my best. Oh, don't have that
thought. That's scary. Like don't Oh,
don't even look at a knife cuz I don't
want to. So many people, they live their
lives
>> in this very like amplified state of
trying to run from their own thoughts.
And that's a terrifying and sad place to
um um convince yourself that that's like
the only place that you get to be in.
Like I I had a lot of success with
allowing the intrusive thoughts to sit
there looking at that damn knife and go,
"Huh, sure. I could do that."
>> Yeah.
>> Let's see. Like just sit with it. W Let
it be wide open. You know what I mean?
So
>> yeah. Yeah, I mean um I just I think
that is that's a masterful that's I
think that's something that I didn't
really think about Blake until you just
said that of like the beauty of us
having conversations with ourselves with
the um assistance of chat GBT or large
language models and helping us realize
what the hell we even think about like
>> you know without being in those real
stakes situations of like dude like you
call your neighbor a racist like now you
you just [__] where you ate now you go
to
and you have an enemy right next door
and you don't really think that you
don't really think that you just had
some
explor
I mean you know more evolved beings can
sit back and have their own thoughts and
meditate and do everything and like be
like no that is wrong I know how I feel
you know but that takes practice that
takes a lot And it's definitely easier,
especially when it's a really deep held
belief. Maybe your belief is I'm bad.
I'm too much.
>> Go and talk to Chat GPT about that. It's
not going to be your therapist, but it's
a good place to go and just say like, I
think I'm bad. Chat GPT is not going to
say you are bad.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> If you're worried about it, just tell it
ahead of time, I'm fragile.
>> Yeah. Sure. And you could do that. And
there's nothing wrong with that. Yeah.
Yeah. you have someone pump you up.
>> Yeah, exactly. I mean, I've told it
before like uh I was working on a
project, I I asked it to give me more
encouragement. I was like, I really like
when you give me encouragement before
you respond. And like, you know, it it
just helped me
>> because if I'm thinking of some creative
idea, I personally get caught up in
like, I'm a [__] loser, dude. What am
I doing? Like, I should be worried about
paying my bills, not making some art on
this wall or whatever. And that's not a
true thought, but it's it's um something
that like I can recognize that I have in
myself and I can cue my LLM to like
remind me that that's untrue.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. You can get it out of your head a
little bit. It's always good to have a
space to do that. You can do the real
work wherever, you know, uh it's like
you were saying before, it's it's not as
black and white as like, oh, this is
therapy, but there's a that people need
something. You know, we can't just keep
going as a society with this idea that
like I'm just gonna hold it in until I'm
around people that agree with me.
>> Yeah. And then Yeah, it feels I think
Yeah. Because then we create echo
chambers and um
>> you know, we we reject we have this this
gift of micro realities, you know, not
not just from the phone, but the phone
is the most exacerbated right in our
face version of it. And we still have a
shared reality. And that's where truth
really is is in our shared reality. But
that doesn't,
you know, the word paradox again, it
doesn't negate this is still a reality.
>> Yeah.
>> You know,
>> and so it's
>> absolutely. Yeah.
>> Yeah. It's um you know, ju just like
your social security number and your
Buddha nature, you know, this is all
this is all true. And so it's you don't
get caught up in trying to argue what
the capital T truth is. We all have our
different realities and we interact in
the shared reality. So if we can make
that more cohesive then
>> hallelujah.
>> Yeah. And do you do you want to be free
or do you want to be right?
>> I love that. That is the best. Uh ask
write that on your hand listener. Write
that on your hand. Print it on a shirt
and just work with that one. That one
could like that's some spiritual
advancement over the next six months.
Just work on that one and you'll see
where you come out on the other side.
>> You definitely get free through it for
sure. It's been lifech changing. Uh
Blake, we're getting up here in time. I
do want to round the corner towards the
end here. Um I want to ask you a
question. I was thinking about this
question. I always come up with like my
my rambling questions are already
impossible for my poor podcast guests,
but I also try to think of like these ex
big existential like um uh you know,
give me the biggest answer to all
questions being asked right here at the
end. So my question for you um at the
end of this podcast here based off of
kind of what we've been talking about
based off of your own life um based off
of our connection, our friendship, we've
been friends for many years and we've
been able to like kind of rekindle the
more recently and it's uh we picked
right picked back up right where we left
off. Man, it's it's very very easy to
connect with you and I really appreciate
that. Um
>> given that
you know that that math guy you talked
about who just like wrote a bunch of
crazy equations and then died the day
after.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Say that the end of this podcast like
say say you're you're going to die
tomorrow and you have this
tongue-in-cheek wisdom of that like you
know like you can now give you have a
microphone in front of you and quote
unquote the world is listening.
>> What what is something that you could
part as you part ways
with this living experience and you
could leave some words of encouragement
or some gift of something with the
world. you had that opportunity, what
would you tell the world?
>> Um,
seek the truth of your deepest being and
be that.
I think that's what I would say.
Poignant.
>> So good.
>> Very direct.
>> I think it encompasses everything for
sure. Yeah.
this guy meditates.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh that's brilliant, man. I I really
like that. I really like that. Um what a
great answer. Uh
>> it's easy to say, you know, everything
is peaceful love and all that kind of
stuff, but I feel like allowing people
to like recognize that in themselves is
better. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And and I love how because I
I think I'm not trying to I don't want
to pick it pick it apart because I think
it's so juicy in itself and everybody
should have have its own, but um Yeah.
It's uh the truth of your being, I
think, is pretty powerful. I think we
get really caught up. I love I love love
religion and theology and spirituality
and all that stuff. Sometimes
that realm gets caught up in like, well,
which one is the truth,
>> you know? Well, which one's true for you
right now? How about that?
>> Oh, I don't I don't really care.
>> Give you an answer.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> I I really do try to practice be here
now as much as possible.
>> Yeah.
>> It's it's really Yeah. It's
whatever whatever anybody wants it to
be. If I'm around Mormons,
we're all LDS today,
>> you know. If I'm around some witches,
cool. Let's do some incantations. That's
cool. You want to talk about
astrologies? You
>> give me a cup of that witches.
>> Yeah.
>> Exactly. Well, I was born on this day,
and that
Yeah, I'm right there. Yeah. Connect to
connect to your truth. Follow your
truth. Yeah. Uh Okay. All right, Blake.
Well,
>> man, thank you so much for your time. I
really appreciate you. Um uh as we end
this thing here. So, uh if if you want
to check out more Blake, I will tag
below. If you want to just follow him on
Instagram, see his thoughts and a little
bit inside of his life, feel free. Uh
Blake, is there anywhere else that you
want to send people? Is there anything
else that you want to um impart with
with these listeners? I don't think so.
Yeah, just uh meditate today.
>> I like it.
>> Best time to start meditating was
yesterday.
>> Yep.
>> Next best is today.
>> And uh zero or uh one is greater than
zero. So don't go thinking that you need
to I need to start my meditation
practice and I'm going to start a six
week meditation journey. If that's what
works for you, that's cool. But
honestly, man, if whatever you got
today, whatever you got tomorrow is just
fine.
>> Five minutes sitting. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Start start meditating. Uh
listener, drink some water. If you have
drank no water today, I don't care what
time it is. This could be 4:00 in the
morning. It's absurd that you have not
drank any water. Please drink some
water. If you haven't stretched today,
you're out of your goddamn mind. You
know the deal. Drop on all fours and
give me some stretches. Please stretch.
Love yourself. Meditate. I have the I
have these like little at the end of all
the podcasts. I obviously
recommendations.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Stretch and drink water is
is a big one. So anyway, thank you guys
for listening. Blake, thank you again
for your time and uh love you guys.
We'll see you on the next one.
[Music]
Knowledge is power.
Reality is
[Music]
Junkyard Love again.